<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xml:base="/en/the-advisory-rss-feed" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#" xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#" xmlns:sioc="http://rdfs.org/sioc/ns#" xmlns:sioct="http://rdfs.org/sioc/types#" xmlns:skos="http://www.w3.org/2004/02/skos/core#" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#">
  <channel>
    <title>The Advisory RSS Feed</title>
    <link>/en/the-advisory-rss-feed</link>
    <description></description>
    <language>en</language>
     <atom:link href="/en/theadvisory.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
    <title>&lt;a href=&quot;/en/en/theadvisory/brown-advisory-latin-american-strategy&quot;&gt;Brown Advisory Latin American Strategy&lt;/a&gt;</title>
    <link>/en/en/theadvisory/brown-advisory-latin-american-strategy</link>
    <description>&lt;h4&gt;
	Q: Can you provide some basic context on the Latin American opportunity?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Well, first things first—this is a big economy and a big opportunity. We are essentially talking about six countries: Argentina, Brazil, Chile, Colombia, Mexico and Peru. Brazil on its own is roughly equal to India in terms of GDP. Taken together, these six countries have a population approaching half a billion people, and produce just under U.S. $5 trillion in GDP&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	A powerful long-term economic transformation is in progress in Latin America. The dictatorships, currency pegs, hyperinflation and guerilla warfare of the 1980s have gradually been replaced in these six countries by democracy, floating currencies, independent central banks and, for the most part, peace. Inflation is a particularly clear window into the transformation in the region; in five of these six countries, inflation has fallen from the 100% range in the 1980s and early 1990s, to low single digits today&amp;nbsp;(Argentina is much earlier in its transformation but following the same model). Middle class growth (from barely 20% of the population in 2002, to more than 35% today&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;) is also transforming Latin America. In addition to its greater purchasing power, the middle class also has something to lose and is thus, in our view,&amp;nbsp;more supportive of governments with pro-business approaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Latin America&amp;nbsp;is one of the last big markets in the world to mature, and we see the potential for top-line growth similar to that of emerging Asia in recent years, possibly with much better bottom-line results. Asia’s GDP growth has often failed to translate into high returns on invested capital (ROIC) for Asian companies. One reason is the ease with which Asian companies can borrow, leading to high debt levels in many cases. In Latin America, high interest rates were the norm for many years, so the best management teams there have real discipline around&amp;nbsp;generating a return on invested capital greater than the cost of capital. This helps them transfer GDP growth more readily to their bottom lines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyLine&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;
	Latin America is Growing Rapidly―Especially Outside of Brazil and Mexico&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;i&gt;Despite various economic challenges faced in the region over the past twenty years, Latin America economic growth has outpaced that of developed markets. Notably some of the fastest growth is in Peru, Colombia and Chile―these countries are a notable weighting of Brown Advisory&#039;s Latin American Strategy relative to the Latin American indexes. The portfolio information provided is based on a representative account and is provided as supplemental information.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;strong&gt;Real GDP Growth Rate by Country/Region (12/31/2000―12/31/2017)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;responsiveImg&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.brownadvisory.com/sites/default/files/u1/latam_gdp_regiongrowth_chart.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Real GDP Growth Rate by Country/Region (12/31/2000―12/31/2018)&quot; src=&quot;http://www.brownadvisory.com/sites/default/files/u1/latam_gdp_regiongrowth_chart.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 14px; font-size: 0.8em;&quot;&gt;
	Source: Bloomberg. Growth rates cited in the right column are annualized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyLine&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;
	Q: You’ve covered Latin America for 20 years. Why do you think the opportunity is particularly attractive now? Conversely, what are some potential downside risks?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	We think that today is a great point of entry into Latin America. First, the region appears to be at an early point in its economic cycle. Latin American economic upturns in the postwar era have all lasted at least five or six&amp;nbsp;years, and this cycle looks particularly promising as all six of our economies are poised to benefit from recent&amp;nbsp;structural reforms, and their currencies are attractively valued vs. the US dollar which should help them compete globally in our view. Corporate margins are not above long-term averages. Economic policy in the region, in our view, offers a fairly benign outlook—interest rates are reasonable (with the notable exception of Argentina), private sector debt is relatively low, and Latin America is not unwinding a major quantitative easing program like many other regions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Second, we believe that currencies in the region are undervalued. We do not try to forecast currency movements, but we always want a view on whether currency is more of a risk or opportunity at a given moment. Right now it appears to be an opportunity—the real effective exchange rate vs. the U.S. dollar is below its 20-year average in most of the markets in which we invest, despite the improved economic conditions in these countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Finally, the valuation picture looks attractive in our view. Our portfolio has generated admirable earnings growth since the strategy&#039;s inception, and the companies we own were producing an adjusted 19% return on equity and had an adjusted 0.8x net debt/EBITDA ratio (excluding financials)&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;nbsp;as of late September 2018.&amp;nbsp;Those are robust results for a portfolio trading at approximately 13x estimated adjusted 2019 earnings – a multiple that should rise if earnings accelerate as we expect&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;. We see this as an unusually low valuation at the beginning of an economic acceleration, offering incremental return potential for proactive investors.&amp;nbsp;So we see all of these economic, currency and valuation factors converging to produce an attractive outlook over a five-plus year time horizon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	There are always risks in emerging markets, however. A recession in the developed world, a Chinese debt crisis, a retrenchment of commodity prices, or a reversal of positive structural trends in these countries--all of these are possibilities that could set Latin American markets back. And the region’s stock markets are still vulnerable to rapid inflows and outflows of foreign capital (an inherent challenge for any emerging market portfolio).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Time has taught us to be patient about the &quot;two steps forward, one step back&quot; pattern that can play out in Latin America. Setbacks occur in different countries at different times, and these situations sometimes—not always—create opportunities for us to add alpha. The latest ongoing example is in Argentina. For the past several years, Argentina’s new pro-market government has been actively reforming the economy—deregulating prices, sorting out the fiscal deficit, sorting out inflation and encouraging private investment. A big part of the country’s economic story is rooted in its agricultural sector, and when it suffered its worst drought in 50 years in 2018, it triggered significant currency weakness and a selloff in its equity markets. The government has responded in an orthodox manner, taking steps such as raising interest rates sharply to stem inflation. We believe that the long-term fundamentals in Argentina are still very promising, and we expect to see the economy recover and re-establish attractive GDP growth in 2019. Given current equity valuations combined with a relatively inexpensive currency, we have had the opportunity to invest in some appealing Argentinian companies at attractive prices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyLine&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;
	The Rise of the Latin American Middle Class&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;i&gt;The middle-class explosion that has driven growth in emerging Asia is also occurring in Latin America. The percentage of Latin American with middle class incomes has risen dramatically since the early 2000s, which has led to a boom in consumer spending and, indirectly, the popularity of more market-friendly governments.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;strong&gt;Middle Class / Poverty Population Trends In Latin America, 2003-2016&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	(Expressed as % of population within daily USD spending ranges)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;responsiveImg&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.brownadvisory.com/sites/default/files/u1/latam_populationpoverty_chart.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;The Rise of the LatAm Middle Class&quot; src=&quot;http://www.brownadvisory.com/sites/default/files/u1/latam_populationpoverty_chart.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 14px; font-size: 0.8em;&quot;&gt;
	Source: World Bank. Poverty level defined as income of approximately $5.50 USD per day or less; middle class defined as income between $13 and $70 USD per day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyLine&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;
	Q: Do you think investors need specific exposure to Latin America?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	We think it makes sense to invest in Latin America, given the bottom-up opportunity and compelling valuations. But benchmark-driven emerging market (EM) strategies don’t offer a lot of Latin American exposure currently. These indexes are market-cap weighted and backward-looking in their construction, so they will not reflect a higher Latin American allocation until share prices have meaningfully rerated in response to the economic resurgence we are seeing in the region. For that reason, we think that investors seeking to capitalize on that resurgence are better served by having specific Latin American exposure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	That being said, we think our value-add is more rooted in stock selection than in regional exposure. We focus primarily on absolute returns, and don’t guide the portfolio relative to any benchmark. One of our portfolio companies, Nutresa, is a good example—we own it for fundamental reasons, not because it gives us exposure to the region or to Colombia. Colombia offers tailwinds to be sure—it’s a free-market democracy where GDP per capita has grown 2.5x since 2000&lt;sup&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt;. But the bulk of our thesis is based on the company itself. We believe that it has excellent brand strength across its core categories including cold cuts, chocolate, pasta and coffee, leading to a 60% aggregate market share in Colombia, which accounts for 60% of its business&lt;sup&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt;. It has a strong distribution network that gives it a competitive advantage against multinational entrants in our view. Moreover, comparisons with other countries strongly suggest that demand for Nutresa’s products will rise as GDP/capita and the middle class grow, so it has an immense runway for growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;
	Q: How does your strategy differentiate from other Latin American strategies?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	We have &lt;strong&gt;a particular focus on &quot;underpenetration” in the portfolio&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;(i.e., situations where an industry has not fully realized its potential in a given country). This focus leads us to companies that have the potential to capture, in essence, three sources of growth. As noted, we believe key Latin American&amp;nbsp;countries are poised for attractive nominal GDP growth; underpenetrated industries offer the potential to grow faster than overall GDP; and finally, our research seeks to uncover companies that can gain share and grow faster than their industries.&amp;nbsp;We believe this focus on underpenetration is a major reason why our portfolio companies have generated strong earnings growth&amp;nbsp;since the strategy&#039;s inception, during a decade-plus period&amp;nbsp;that we would describe as peak-to-trough for the region&#039;s economies.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Additionally, we believe that &lt;strong&gt;our benchmark-agnostic approach offers greater diversification&lt;/strong&gt; of country and currency risk than benchmark-driven strategies.The MSCI Latin American Index is market-cap weighted, so Brazilian and Mexican companies can represent as much as 80% of the Index at times. The Index can also have meaningful weights in companies that we think are unattractive from a fundamental standpoint— state-owned businesses with poor governance influenced by politics, energy and other commodity companies, and companies in slower-growth sectors like telecom. Petrobras—driven by the inherently unpredictable price of oil, and governed by political appointees that change with every election—is a good example; it&#039;s a large constituent within the Index, but it is not the kind of model we want to back with our clients’ capital.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	In contrast, we seek to invest broadly across countries with solid long-term fundamentals and improving policy environments, and in high-quality growth stocks with long growth runways that operate in clearly underpenetrated domestic industries. Our portfolio is more diversified than the Index across the six major economies in Latin America (for example, Peru made up about 15% of our portfolio as of June 30, 2018, vs. only about 4% of the Index&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;). We only invest in &quot;private&quot; (i.e., not state controlled) companies with managers clearly aligned with shareholder interest; we don’t invest in state-controlled companies and we avoid commodity and low-growth stocks; and, we only invest in companies where we think long run results are relatively predictable and we believe that profits will compound well over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	A benchmark-agnostic approach will inevitably have periods when it exceeds and lags benchmark indexes that other strategies track more closely. However, over the long term our strategy has generated higher returns than the MSCI Latin American Index, at similar levels of volatility, since its 2006 inception.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Finally, we believe that we know these markets very well after many years of visiting and investing in Latin America. There are about 100-150 companies of real interest to us. We each visit the region several times per year, so between us we usually spend 15-20 weeks a year in the countries we invest in and conduct 300-400 meetings with this select list of firms each year. In addition, we attend Latin American conferences&amp;nbsp;and meet Latin American companies in London when they are doing non-deal roadshows (many come to London once or twice per year). So we’re very close to the data and to each company’s strategy and management team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;
	Q: How can investors access the strategy?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Investors can access the strategy through the existing UCITS Fund or through a segregated mandate. In the U.S., the strategy is available via segregated mandate, and we have plans to launch an SEC-registered mutual fund in the near future.&amp;nbsp;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/sites/default/files/u1/b-box-logo.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 12px; height: 16px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10px;&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;Source: World Economic Outlook Database, April 2018, International Monetary Fund.&lt;br /&gt;
	&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;Source: The World Bank, LAC Equity Lab: Poverty – Poverty Rate. Data from 2000–2016 updated and published in April 2018.&lt;br /&gt;
	&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;Source: Bloomberg, Brown Advisory and broker estimates. Characteristics exclude cash and cash equivalents.The return on equity or &lt;strong&gt;ROE&lt;/strong&gt; figure cited is an adjusted trailing 12-month weighted average. Companies with a negative ROE were removed from the calculation. The calculation is&amp;nbsp;as of Sept. 19, 2018. Further details on calculation methodology are available on request.&amp;nbsp;The unadjusted ROE is 17.0%. The unadjusted estimated 2019 earnings are 13.9x. The portfolio information provided is based on a representative account and is provided as supplemental information.&lt;br /&gt;
	&lt;sup&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt;Source: International Monetary Fund.&lt;br /&gt;
	&lt;sup&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt;Source: Grupo Nutresa Corporate Presentation/Fact Sheet.&lt;br /&gt;
	&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;Source: Brown Advisory.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyLine&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.brownadvisory.com/disclosures/latin-american-composite&quot;&gt;Click here to view Latin American Composite Disclosures&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	The views expressed are those of Brown Advisory as of the date referenced and are subject to change at any time based on market or other conditions. These views are not intended to be and should not be relied upon as investment advice and are not intended to be a forecast of future events or a guarantee of future results. Past performance is not a guarantee of future performance and you may not get back the amount invested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;padding: 5px 0px 0px; line-height: 1.5em; font-size: 0.7em;&quot;&gt;
	The information provided in this material is not intended to be and should not be considered to be a recommendation or suggestion to engage in or refrain from a particular course of action or to make or hold a particular investment or pursue a particular investment strategy, including whether or not to buy, sell, or hold any of the securities or asset classes mentioned. It should not be assumed that investments in such securities or asset classes have been or will be profitable. To the extent specific securities are mentioned, they have been selected by the author on an objective basis to illustrate views expressed in the commentary and do not represent all of the securities purchased, sold or recommended for advisory clients. The information contained herein has been prepared from sources believed reliable but is not guaranteed by us as to its timeliness or accuracy, and is not a complete summary or statement of all available data. This piece is intended solely for our clients and prospective clients, is for informational purposes only, and is not individually tailored for or directed to any particular client or prospective client.&lt;br /&gt;
	&lt;br /&gt;
	&lt;strong&gt;Return on Invested Capital (ROIC)&lt;/strong&gt; measures a company&#039;s profitability in the context of the capital it invests in its business. It is calculated as NOPAT/IC; where NOPAT (net operating profit after tax) is (EBIT + Operating Leases Due 1-Yr)*(1-Cash Tax Rate) and IC (invested capital) is Total Debt + Total Equity + Total Unfunded Pension + (Operating Leases Due 1-Yr * 8) –ExcessCash.&lt;br /&gt;
	&lt;br /&gt;
	&lt;strong&gt;Alpha&lt;/strong&gt; is used in finance as a measure of performance. Alpha, often considered the active return on an investment, gauges the performance of an investment against a market index or benchmark which is considered to represent the market’s movement as a whole. The excess return of an investment relative to the return of a benchmark index is the investment’s alpha.&lt;br /&gt;
	&lt;br /&gt;
	The &lt;strong&gt;MSCI Emerging Markets (EM) Latin America Index&lt;/strong&gt; captures large and mid cap representation across 5 Emerging Markets (EM) countries in Latin America which include: Brazil, Chile, Colombia, Mexico, and Peru. With 109 constituents, the index covers approximately 85% of the free float-adjusted market capitalization in each country.&lt;br /&gt;
	BLOOMBERG, BLOOMBERG PROFESSIONAL, BLOOMBERG MARKETS, BLOOMBERG NEWS,BLOOMBERG ANYWHERE, BLOOMBERG TRADEBOOK, BLOOMBERG BONDTRADER, BLOOMBERG TELEVISION, BLOOMBERG RADIO, BLOOMBERG PRESS, BLOOMBERG.COM and BLOOMBERG LAW are trademarks and service marks of Bloomberg Finance L.P., a Delaware limited partnership, or its subsidiaries.&lt;br /&gt;
	All MSCI indexes and products are trademarks and service marks of MSCI or its subsidiaries.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     <pubDate>Friday, October 5, 2018 - 09:55</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Rupert Brandt, CFA, Peter Cawston</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">&lt;a href=&quot;/en/theadvisory/brown-advisory-latin-american-strategy&quot;&gt;24901&lt;/a&gt;</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>&lt;a href=&quot;/en/en/theadvisory/why-invest-europe-and-asia-even-us-stocks-charge-ahead&quot;&gt;Why Invest in Europe and Asia (Even as U.S. Stocks Charge Ahead)?&lt;/a&gt;</title>
    <link>/en/en/theadvisory/why-invest-europe-and-asia-even-us-stocks-charge-ahead</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;
	Diversification is a powerful tool for investors. It makes sense to spread investments into different asset classes and different global regions to balance risk and reward. But in recent years, a number of investors—especially those in the U.S.—have started to question why they should allocate to non-U.S. equities at all. U.S. stocks have generally been clear outperformers since the 2008-09 financial crisis, and it hasn’t really been close: Over the ten years since the financial crisis, U.S. equities have returned more than 11% per year (for USD-based investors), while outside the U.S., equity returns were closer to 5% per year for the same period. (For currency-hedged investors, the difference is less dramatic due to currency trends over this period, but the basic narrative is the same.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Recency bias is a powerful force, and it drives many smart people to assume that what they have seen recently is the “new normal.” But the truth is that the return differential between U.S. and non-U.S. stock has cycled back and forth regularly for many decades. There is no reason to expect that this cycle has ended, and/or that one side has somehow “won.” Moreover, despite persistent strength in U.S. markets ten years after the financial crisis, there are a number of fundamental factors supporting a “relative comeback” for both developed and emerging non-U.S. markets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyLine&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;
	The U.S. / Non-U.S. Stock Contest: A Split Decision, Historically&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;i&gt;A quick review of recent history shows that picking either side of this contest would have left you sorely disappointed in your choice during many of the past 40 years:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;strong&gt;Relative Performance, U.S. Equities vs. Non-U.S. Equities (USD)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
	One-Year Rolling Time Periods (12/31/79—9/30/18)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;responsiveImg&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brownadvisory.com/sites/default/files/u1/globaldiversification_chart.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Relative Difference Between U.S. and Non-U.S. Equity (USD) Returns&quot; src=&quot;https://www.brownadvisory.com/sites/default/files/u1/globaldiversification_chart.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 14px; font-size: 0.8em;&quot;&gt;
	Source: Bloomberg. U.S. equities are represented by the Russell 3000® Index. Non-U.S. equities are represented by the MSCI EAFE Index from 1979-1987, and the MSCI ACWI ex. U.S. Index from 1988-2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyLine&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	In the 1980s, non-U.S. stocks were big winners over the U.S., as Japanese markets boomed and the U.S. “Black Monday” crash in 1987, among other factors, weighed on market returns. Then, in the 1990s, U.S. stocks benefited greatly from an internet-driven technology renaissance, while later in the decade non-U.S. markets were stung by the Asian Financial Crisis in 1997 and the Russian government debt default a year later. The 2000s were another period of broad outperformance for non-U.S. stocks, and as we’ve noted, U.S. stocks have reigned since the global financial crisis of 2008-09.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	We see here a general pattern of multiyear cycles when one “side” of this equation outperforms the other, and a series of boom and bust events that would have been difficult to predict in advance, but ended up benefiting or hurting one region over others in an outsized manner. None of this was easily predictable before it happened—and in truth, none of it offers much in the way of predictive value for us going forward. But we know that regional results have varied wildly over the years, and fortunes have shifted quickly. Against that backdrop, we think the best way to earn attractive returns while reducing risk is to diversify one’s portfolio across the globe. And by diversification, we mean balance in allocation less from quarter to quarter, or year to year, but rather over long periods, to balance when one region or the other struggles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;
	Continental Confidence: A Review of our Approach to European Equities&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	However, diversifying blindly takes away one’s ability to make educated choices on markets that look fundamentally attractive. We strike a balance—we seek broad diversification, then lean our weightings in one direction or another based on our fundamental outlook for various regions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	For several years after the crisis, we consciously underweighted Europe; austerity as well as the economies of Greece and several other “peripheral” EU nations held back Europe’s recovery relative to the U.S. Our clients in Europe have a different starting point for geographic equity weightings than those in the U.S. (investors typically use benchmarks that emphasize home markets, to align risk with their home economies and currencies), but across the board we recommended a tilt away from Europe and toward the U.S.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Then, after six years we regained a greater degree of optimism about Europe and began shifting assets back in that direction, as we noted in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brownadvisory.com/en/theadvisory/european-re-entry-why-we-are-shifting-portfolios-toward-european-stocks&quot;&gt;an article in 2017&lt;/a&gt;. Europe’s economic picture had improved markedly at the time, with debt crises fading into the rearview mirror and broader leading indicators such as purchasing manager sentiment heading in the right direction. Equity valuations in Europe at the time were more attractive than those in the U.S. These arguments still generally hold today in our view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	We should note that at both ends of this decision-making spectrum, our shifts were incremental, not dramatic, and represented overall movements of 3-4% of our overall portfolio mix. We may look back in 12-18 months and see that our recent incremental shift toward Europe was slightly positive or negative. But we believe we will feel comfortable with our decision to remain invested globally, so we have the potential to capture opportunity and weather risk in a balanced manner.&amp;nbsp;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/sites/default/files/u1/b-box-logo.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 12px; height: 16px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyLine&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	The views expressed are those of Brown Advisory as of the date referenced and are subject to change at any time based on market or other conditions. These views are not intended to be and should not be relied upon as investment advice and are not intended to be a forecast of future events or a guarantee of future results. Past performance is not a guarantee of future performance and you may not get back the amount invested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;padding: 5px 0px 0px; line-height: 1.5em; font-size: 0.7em;&quot;&gt;
	The information provided in this material is not intended to be and should not be considered to be a recommendation or suggestion to engage in or refrain from a particular course of action or to make or hold a particular investment or pursue a particular investment strategy, including whether or not to buy, sell, or hold any of the securities or asset classes mentioned. It should not be assumed that investments in such securities or asset classes have been or will be profitable. To the extent specific securities are mentioned, they have been selected by the author on an objective basis to illustrate views expressed in the commentary and do not represent all of the securities purchased, sold or recommended for advisory clients. The information contained herein has been prepared from sources believed reliable but is not guaranteed by us as to its timeliness or accuracy, and is not a complete summary or statement of all available data. This piece is intended solely for our clients and prospective clients, is for informational purposes only, and is not individually tailored for or directed to any particular client or prospective client.&lt;br /&gt;
	&lt;br /&gt;
	&lt;strong&gt;Russell 3000® Index&lt;/strong&gt; is a market-capitalization-weighted equity index maintained by the FTSE Russell that provides exposure to the entire U.S. stock market. The index tracks the performance of the 3,000 largest U.S.-traded stocks which represent about 98% of all U.S incorporated equity securities.&lt;br /&gt;
	“FTSE®”, “Russell®”, “MTS®”, “FTSE TMX®” and “FTSE Russell” and other service marks and trademarks related to the FTSE or Russell indexes are trademarks of the London Stock Exchange Group companies.&lt;br /&gt;
	&lt;strong&gt;MSCI EAFE Index&lt;/strong&gt; is a stock market index that is designed to measure the equity market performance of developed markets outside of the U.S. &amp;amp; Canada. It is maintained by MSCI Inc., a provider of investment decision support tools; the EAFE acronym stands for Europe, Australasia and Far East.&lt;br /&gt;
	&lt;strong&gt;MSCI All Country World Index&lt;/strong&gt; Ex-U.S. (MSCI ACWI Ex-U.S.) is a market-capitalization-weighted index maintained by Morgan Stanley Capital International (MSCI) The MSCI All Country World Index Ex-U.S. includes both developed and emerging markets.&lt;br /&gt;
	All MSCI indexes and products are trademarks and service marks of MSCI or its subsidiaries.&lt;br /&gt;
	BLOOMBERG, BLOOMBERG PROFESSIONAL, BLOOMBERG MARKETS, BLOOMBERG NEWS,BLOOMBERG ANYWHERE, BLOOMBERG TRADEBOOK, BLOOMBERG BONDTRADER, BLOOMBERG TELEVISION, BLOOMBERG RADIO, BLOOMBERG PRESS, BLOOMBERG.COM and BLOOMBERG LAW are trademarks and service marks of Bloomberg Finance L.P., a Delaware limited partnership, or its subsidiaries.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     <pubDate>Tuesday, October 2, 2018 - 14:44</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Taylor Graff, CFA, J.R. Rodrigo</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">&lt;a href=&quot;/en/theadvisory/why-invest-europe-and-asia-even-us-stocks-charge-ahead&quot;&gt;24981&lt;/a&gt;</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>&lt;a href=&quot;/en/en/theadvisory/mortgage-market-ten-years-later&quot;&gt;The Mortgage Market: Ten Years Later&lt;/a&gt;</title>
    <link>/en/en/theadvisory/mortgage-market-ten-years-later</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;
	In San Francisco’s historic Sunset District, there is a charming 1,289 square-foot 2-bedroom home, brimming with potential. That potential stems not from its character, but from its price tag: At $995,000, it is one of the few homes on the market in San Francisco for less than $1 million, and far below the city’s staggering median home price of $1.62 million.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	We’re nearly ten years removed from the 2008-09 mortgage crisis, and one symbol of the recovery is the broad rise in home prices across the country. But in the past year or so, some investors have grown concerned that another potential crisis is around the corner, citing data points such as the eye-popping prices in markets like San Francisco, as well as recent housing starts reports that suggest slowing growth in new construction. While these data points deserve attention, we believe that the broader array of data reveals a much healthier mortgage market than the one that existed before the 2008-09 crisis. While a housing pullback may be inevitable, the mortgage market is in much better shape, in our view, to weather it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyLine&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
	Chart 1: Delinquency Rates Falling; Inflation-Adjusted Home Prices Well Below Pre-Crisis Peak, 2000-2017&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot; class=&quot;responsiveImg&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.brownadvisory.com/sites/default/files/u1/chartsmortgage_bar.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Chart 1: Delinquency Rates Falling; Inflation-Adjusted Home Prices Well Below Pre-Crisis Peak&quot; src=&quot;http://www.brownadvisory.com/sites/default/files/u1/chartsmortgage_bar.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 790px; height: 460px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 14px; font-size: 0.8em;&quot;&gt;
	Source: Mortgage Delinquency Rate: Federal Reserve Economic Data (FRED); Home Price Index: Brown Advisory calculation derived by subtracting the housing component of the Consumer Price Index from the S&amp;amp;P/Case-Shiller 20-City Composite Home Price Index.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyLine&quot;&gt;
	&lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;
			As shown in the chart above, delinquencies have fallen for eight straight years, reaching a cycle low of 3.7% in 2017, down from a peak of 10.9% in 2010. This metric still has a ways to go before it reaches the sub-2% level we last saw in 2005-2006, and there is fundamental room for improvement (legacy assets from the crisis era are still working through the foreclosure pipeline).&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;
			Additionally, home prices are indeed lofty in the Bay Area and several other regions, but price trends vary widely regionally. National prices have surpassed their peak in 2006 on a nominal basis, but after adjusting for home-price inflation, current real prices are still 24% below that peak level (shown in Chart 1).&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;

	&lt;div class=&quot;greyLine&quot;&gt;
		&lt;a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

	&lt;h4 align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
		Chart 2: Subprime Mortgage Origination Has Declined To Negligible Levels&lt;/h4&gt;

	&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
		(Mix of Borrower FICO Scores: Non-agency Mortgage Origination, 2005 vs. 2017)&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot; class=&quot;responsiveImg&quot;&gt;
		&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.brownadvisory.com/sites/default/files/u1/wave_chartsmortgage2.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Chart 2: Subprime Mortgage Origination Has Declined To Negligible Levels&quot; src=&quot;http://www.brownadvisory.com/sites/default/files/u1/wave_chartsmortgage2.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 790px; height: 464px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 14px; font-size: 0.8em;&quot;&gt;
		Source: Goldman Sachs&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;div class=&quot;greyLine&quot;&gt;
		&lt;a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

	&lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;
			This chart highlights how much underwriting standards have tightened since the financial crisis. The quality mix of newly originated loans is much higher today relative to pre-crisis mortgages. In 2005, non-agency lending was a huge component of the lending market, but today, government-backed mortgages represent the vast majority of the market. And, within that non-agency lending segment, loans to subprime borrowers make up less than 1.5% of total originations (using a credit score of 640 or lower as a cutoff metric for subprime). In contrast, in 2005 nearly 25% of non-agency borrowers had scores below 640. Simply put, subprime lending was the root of the mortgage crisis, and from a big-picture perspective, subprime lending makes up only a tiny sliver of today’s mortgage market.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;
		We understand the concerns some investors have expressed: For years, the central narrative supporting rising home prices was limited inventory and new construction that wasn’t keeping pace with demand. Recent data challenged that thesis. Below-consensus numbers for new housing starts and existing home sales in the past few months suggested to some that the supply crunch had dissipated.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;
		But it is dangerous to extrapolate big conclusions from single data points. The housing market is a product of a multitude of variables—existing home sales, inventory figures, construction spending, mortgage delinquencies and broad credit mix in the MBS market are just a few of many indicators that fixed income investors should consider when looking at the mortgage market. Housing prices may pull back eventually, and interest rates and other factors could impact mortgage pricing in the short term, but from a fundamental perspective, the mortgage market appears to us to be on solid ground.&amp;nbsp;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/sites/default/files/u1/b-box-logo.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 12px; height: 16px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;br /&gt;
	&lt;br /&gt;
	&amp;nbsp;
	&lt;div class=&quot;greyLine&quot;&gt;
		&lt;a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;
		The views expressed are those of Brown Advisory as of the date referenced and are subject to change at any time based on market or other conditions. These views are not intended to be and should not be relied upon as investment advice and are not intended to be a forecast of future events or a guarantee of future results. Past performance is not a guarantee of future performance and you may not get back the amount invested.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p style=&quot;padding: 5px 0px 0px; line-height: 1.5em; font-size: 0.7em;&quot;&gt;
		The information provided in this material is not intended to be and should not be considered to be a recommendation or suggestion to engage in or refrain from a particular course of action or to make or hold a particular investment or pursue a particular investment strategy, including whether or not to buy, sell, or hold any of the securities or asset classes mentioned. It should not be assumed that investments in such securities or asset classes have been or will be profitable. To the extent specific securities are mentioned, they have been selected by the author on an objective basis to illustrate views expressed in the commentary and do not represent all of the securities purchased, sold or recommended for advisory clients. The information contained herein has been prepared from sources believed reliable but is not guaranteed by us as to its timeliness or accuracy, and is not a complete summary or statement of all available data. This piece is intended solely for our clients and prospective clients, is for informational purposes only, and is not individually tailored for or directed to any particular client or prospective client.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
     <pubDate>Tuesday, September 11, 2018 - 08:19</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>John Henry Iucker</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">&lt;a href=&quot;/en/theadvisory/mortgage-market-ten-years-later&quot;&gt;24651&lt;/a&gt;</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>&lt;a href=&quot;/en/en/theadvisory/diversification-design-why-we-don%25E2%2580%2599t-hug-muni-benchmark&quot;&gt;Diversification by Design: Why We Don’t Hug the Muni Benchmark&lt;/a&gt;</title>
    <link>/en/en/theadvisory/diversification-design-why-we-don%25E2%2580%2599t-hug-muni-benchmark</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;
	The total municipal universe has over one million individual securities. Most muni indexes hold tens of thousands of bonds—the benchmark for our National Muni strategy, for example, is the Bloomberg Barclays Municipal 1-10 Year Blend Index, and it holds a constantly changing roster of more than 30,000 securities. The question all managers face: How can one track and/or outperform such a vast index, when owning the full index is essentially impossible?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Many managers feel obligated to adhere to benchmark parameters—they may adjust duration or seek out attractive bonds as part of their process, but they still largely stick to their benchmark’s duration, credit and sector boundaries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	We are very different. We invest from the bottom up and build portfolios one bond at a time—an approach that often leads to credit and sector weightings that are quite different from our benchmark. We are not intentionally making bets in relation to our benchmark; rather, we build portfolios based on where we see risk and relative value in the market. Where others may consider benchmark divergence as a risk, we see it as an incidental outcome of our search for greater value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;
	WHY WE ARE NOT BENCHMARK-DRIVEN&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	A problem with any top-down, index-driven approach, in our view, is that it chains the portfolio to an index of securities &lt;strong&gt;&lt;i&gt;that is not in any way discerning about its constituents&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. There is nothing magical about the securities in these indexes. Our benchmark includes literally every fixed-rate bond issuance in the U.S. that meets certain criteria (such as deal size and maturity range), regardless of merit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	In contrast, we start from zero, and build our portfolios from the ground up. Our portfolios differ from our benchmark, because our goal differs from the benchmark’s goal. The benchmark seeks to represent every eligible investment in the universe—the benchmark does not care if those securities expose investors to risks they consider important. We seek to offer performance within a risk tolerance defined by the client, so we invest where we see relative value—NOT where a benchmark tells us to invest. (Our recent publication, “&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.brownadvisory.com/en/theadvisory/its-all-relative&quot;&gt;It’s All Relative&lt;/a&gt;,” offers a deeper dive into our team’s philosophy and process for building portfolios and selecting securities).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;
	OUR PORTFOLIO TODAY&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	The chart below highlights several of the more notable overweights and underweights in our National Muni portfolio as of June 30, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyLine&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;
	Diversification by Design: National Muni Portfolio vs. Bloomberg Barclays&lt;br /&gt;
	Municipal 1-10 Year Blend Index&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 1em;&quot;&gt;
	&lt;i&gt;Our strategy focuses entirely on finding securities that offer relative value compared to the rest of the available universe. This approach often leads to portfolios with very different credit, sector and duration weightings than the benchmark—to be clear, these are NOT top-down bets, but rather results of a bottom-up process.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot; class=&quot;responsiveImg&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.brownadvisory.com/sites/default/files/u1/diverse_chart2.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Diversification by Design: National Muni Portfolio vs. Bloomberg Barclays Municipal 1-10 Year Blend Index&quot; src=&quot;http://www.brownadvisory.com/sites/default/files/u1/diverse_chart2.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 790px; height: 545px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 14px; font-size: 0.8em;&quot;&gt;
	Source: Bloomberg as of 6/30/18. The portfolio information is based on a representative National Municipal Bond account and is provided as supplemental information. Portfolio level information includes cash and cash equivalents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyLine&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Our underweight in AAA bonds and overweight in BBB bonds has been a fairly consistent trend for the portfolio. We traditionally find a healthy number of bonds in the BBB and A range that, in our view, offer a favorable mix of potential return and risk. Our credit research process gives us confidence to own these bonds; in a number of these cases, we find that the issuer’s credit profile has improved markedly over a period of years, but the agencies have been slow to upgrade their ratings. On the other hand, demand for AAA-rated munis historically has been supported by a large segment of investors seeking safety that simply want to minimize credit risk as much as possible. As such, we find that the value offered by these AAA securities is less than compelling during many points in the credit cycle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	We also hold a fairly large weighting in variable-rate bonds; our benchmark, due to its eligibility requirements, holds no variable-rate securities. We feel that short-duration fixed-rate municipals are currently overvalued—with widespread anxiety about rising interest rates among bond investors, many are gravitating to the short end of the yield curve. The variable-rate short-term securities that we own currently offer yields that are compelling compared to fixed-rate bonds, while having far less interest rate exposure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Both of these examples highlight the opportunities available within a bottom-up, fundamental approach to investing. We feel our clients are far better served by an independent mindset and a process that focuses on relative value, not by one that is strictly beholden to a benchmark.&amp;nbsp;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/sites/default/files/u1/b-box-logo.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 12px; height: 16px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyLine&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.brownadvisory.com/disclosures/muni-composite&quot;&gt;Click here to view National Municipal Bond Composite Disclosures&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	The views expressed are those of Brown Advisory as of the date referenced and are subject to change at any time based on market or other conditions. These views are not intended to be and should not be relied upon as investment advice and are not intended to be a forecast of future events or a guarantee of future results. Past performance is not a guarantee of future performance and you may not get back the amount invested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;padding: 5px 0px 0px; line-height: 1.5em; font-size: 0.7em;&quot;&gt;
	The information provided in this material is not intended to be and should not be considered to be a recommendation or suggestion to engage in or refrain from a particular course of action or to make or hold a particular investment or pursue a particular investment strategy, including whether or not to buy, sell, or hold any of the securities or asset classes mentioned. It should not be assumed that investments in such securities or asset classes have been or will be profitable. To the extent specific securities are mentioned, they have been selected by the author on an objective basis to illustrate views expressed in the commentary and do not represent all of the securities purchased, sold or recommended for advisory clients. The information contained herein has been prepared from sources believed reliable but is not guaranteed by us as to its timeliness or accuracy, and is not a complete summary or statement of all available data. This piece is intended solely for our clients and prospective clients, is for informational purposes only, and is not individually tailored for or directed to any particular client or prospective client.&lt;br /&gt;
	&lt;br /&gt;
	Bloomberg Barclays 1-10 Year Municipal Blend (1-12) Index is a market value-weighted index which covers the short and intermediate components of the Bloomberg Barclays U.S. Municipal Index. It tracks tax-exempt municipal General Obligation, Revenue, Insured, and Prerefunded bonds with a minimum $5 million par amount outstanding, issued as part of a transaction of at least $50 million, and with a remaining maturity from 1 up to (but not including) 12 years. Both indexes include reinvestment of income. One can not invest directly in an index.&lt;br /&gt;
	Bloomberg Barclays Indices are trademarks of Bloomberg or its licensors, including Barclays Bank PLC.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     <pubDate>Thursday, August 23, 2018 - 09:32</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Joshua Perry, CFA, CAIA, FRM, Stephen Shutz, CFA</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">&lt;a href=&quot;/en/theadvisory/diversification-design-why-we-don%E2%80%99t-hug-muni-benchmark&quot;&gt;24611&lt;/a&gt;</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>&lt;a href=&quot;/en/en/theadvisory/four-companies-are-spending-hundreds-billions-building-cloud&quot;&gt;Four Companies Are Spending Hundreds of Billions Building The Cloud&lt;/a&gt;</title>
    <link>/en/en/theadvisory/four-companies-are-spending-hundreds-billions-building-cloud</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;
	The titans of technology have continually led the news cycle in recent years, as their reach has extended—for better or worse—into every corner of our lives. The big tech companies also have been generating exceptional stock returns: Facebook, Google, Microsoft and Amazon have together driven an outsized proportion of S&amp;amp;P 500&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px;&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;®&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt; Index returns over the past several years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	These four companies are traditionally viewed as “asset-light” business models, but more recently their capital expenditures have skyrocketed. This trend has led to some questions about the future—are above-average returns on capital at these companies sustainable? Is their profitability in jeopardy? For now, we see the growth in cap ex at these firms in a positive light, because the assets they&amp;nbsp;are building are, in our view, essential components of their long-term competitive moats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	The magnitude of the growth in cap ex for these firms is staggering (all data in this article sourced from Factset):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		Between 2015 and 2019, Facebook, Google, Amazon and Microsoft are on track to drive &lt;em&gt;79&lt;/em&gt;&lt;i&gt;% of all incremental cap ex&lt;/i&gt; of S&amp;amp;P 500 Index companies.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		The four firms are expected to grow cap ex at over 31% per year, while the rest of the S&amp;amp;P 500 Index companies grow their capital spending by only 0.5% per year.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		When all is said and done, the four firms are expected to be driving about 11% of all capital expenditures across the S&amp;amp;P 500 Index universe by the end of 2019.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyLine&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
	Amazon, Facebook, Google, Microsoft Capital Expenditure Growth Trend, 2015-2019E&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot; style=&quot;font-size: 1em;&quot;&gt;
	Four Companies Are Expected To Represent 11% of S&amp;amp;P 500 Index Cap Ex by 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot; class=&quot;responsiveImg&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.brownadvisory.com/sites/default/files/u1/capex_chart3.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Amazon, Facebook, Google, Microsoft Capital Expenditure Growth Trend, 2015-2019E&quot; src=&quot;http://www.brownadvisory.com/sites/default/files/u1/capex_chart3.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 780px; height: 419px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 14px; font-size: 0.8em;&quot;&gt;
	Source: Factset as of 7/31/18.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyLine&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	At first glance these numbers may seem like a mistake; after all, software and internet companies don’t build factories or manage massive logistical networks. But in fact, these companies are building data centers—the effective equivalent of factories and cargo networks for the internet—at a breakneck clip, because they are increasingly shouldering the burden of the entire economy’s enterprise data and application needs, not to mention the storage and management of the world’s texts, emails, photos and videos (excluding China, which is another topic entirely). As companies across the economy become more comfortable moving their key business applications to the cloud, and platforms like Facebook, Instagram, YouTube and Twitch continue their exponential growth, it is no wonder that these four firms are on pace to grow aggregate cap ex—largely driven by data center spending—from $23 billion in 2015 to a whopping $68 billion in 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	This shift is meaningful for these firms’ business models, as their aggregate cap ex has risen from 5.5% of sales in 2012 to 12% in 2018. But we view this rising capital intensity as less of a concern about profitability, and more of a positive sign for their ability to sustain market leadership well into the future. For one, the assets they are building will make it extremely hard if not impossible for other entrants to come along and compete on equal footing to deliver data storage and processing capacity. Moreover, they are in optimal position for the coming wave of artificial intelligence (AI) innovation. Various forms of AI have been theoretically possible for decades, but AI is now finally applicable in practical terms thanks to the scale of today’s datasets and the reduced cost of storage and processing; in fact, infrastructure to enable AI is one of the drivers behind the growth in cap ex we have been discussing. These four firms are leveraging their scale and making massive investments in AI capabilities, in an effort to enhance their value to&amp;nbsp;enterprise customers, and make them even more reluctant to look elsewhere for a primary technology solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Technology is driven by innovation and disruption, so we can never be sure what surprises lay ahead for the sector or for the companies we’ve discussed here. But we believe that the heavy capital investments being made by these firms are leading to important assets that can support the long-term sustainability of their business models.&amp;nbsp;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/sites/default/files/u1/b-box-logo.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 12px; height: 16px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyLine&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	The views expressed are those of Brown Advisory as of the date referenced and are subject to change at any time based on market or other conditions. These views are not intended to be and should not be relied upon as investment advice and are not intended to be a forecast of future events or a guarantee of future results. Past performance is not a guarantee of future performance and you may not get back the amount invested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;padding: 5px 0px 0px; line-height: 1.5em; font-size: 0.7em;&quot;&gt;
	The information provided in this material is not intended to be and should not be considered to be a recommendation or suggestion to engage in or refrain from a particular course of action or to make or hold a particular investment or pursue a particular investment strategy, including whether or not to buy, sell, or hold any of the securities or asset classes mentioned. It should not be assumed that investments in such securities or asset classes have been or will be profitable. To the extent specific securities are mentioned, they have been selected by the author on an objective basis to illustrate views expressed in the commentary and do not represent all of the securities purchased, sold or recommended for advisory clients. The information contained herein has been prepared from sources believed reliable but is not guaranteed by us as to its timeliness or accuracy, and is not a complete summary or statement of all available data. This piece is intended solely for our clients and prospective clients, is for informational purposes only, and is not individually tailored for or directed to any particular client or prospective client.&lt;br /&gt;
	&lt;br /&gt;
	The S&amp;amp;P 500® Index represents the large-cap segment of the U.S. equity markets and consists of approximately 500 leading companies in leading industries of the U.S. economy. Criteria evaluated include market capitalization, financial viability, liquidity, public float, sector representation and corporate structure. An index constituent must also be considered a U.S. company. Standard &amp;amp; Poor’s, S&amp;amp;P®, and S&amp;amp;P 500® are registered trademarks of Standard &amp;amp; Poor’s Financial Services LLC (“S&amp;amp;P”), a subsidiary of S&amp;amp;P Global Inc.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     <pubDate>Monday, August 20, 2018 - 08:24</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>John Canning, CFA</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">&lt;a href=&quot;/en/theadvisory/four-companies-are-spending-hundreds-billions-building-cloud&quot;&gt;24591&lt;/a&gt;</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>&lt;a href=&quot;/en/en/theadvisory/spin-city-new-wave-deconglomeratization&quot;&gt;Spin City: The New Wave of Deconglomeratization&lt;/a&gt;</title>
    <link>/en/en/theadvisory/spin-city-new-wave-deconglomeratization</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;
	The biggest media story in the industrial space this summer has been the accelerating breakup of General Electric. For many decades, GE was the shining example for conglomerates everywhere—Jack Welch’s model of pursuing a #1 or #2 position across many industries was one of the most well-known business strategies in the world. But in recent years, calls for a GE breakup reached a fever pitch, and the company is taking action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Deconglomeratization—a big word for breaking up or spinning off parts of a conglomerate—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.inc.com/magazine/19830801/3871.html&quot;&gt;is not a new idea&lt;/a&gt;. But the pace of spinoff activity has definitely picked up of late. Through July of this year, more than 100 companies have announced spinoff plans, according to Bloomberg—that represents a 54% spike in activity vs. the same period last year and the highest level of activity in at least a decade. So why now? Beyond GE, why has the activist cry for “deconglomeratization” across the industrial sector gained such momentum?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	There are several reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;
			&lt;strong&gt;Too much diversification.&lt;/strong&gt; In any given quarter, conglomerates typically have a mix of stronger and weaker performers among their business units. Sometimes, the bad offsets the good, so the company struggles to produce exceptional overall results in any given reporting period. In the multiyear bull market we’ve experienced since 2009, shareholders perceive these situations as persistently mediocre.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;
			&lt;strong&gt;Struggling under their own weight. &lt;/strong&gt;Sprawling conglomerates inevitably grow more complex over time, leading to inefficiency and paralyzing bureaucracy. Middling stock performance and clunky operations make it difficult for such companies to recruit or retain top talent. Also, the internal competition among business units for funding often leads to capital allocation processes governed more by organizational politics than by business merits.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;
			&lt;strong&gt;Desire for transparency. &lt;/strong&gt;Management teams of conglomerates can massage their quarterly earnings reports to fit their preferred narrative, or they can simply decline to provide granular results at the business-unit level. Thus, it is difficult for investors to evaluate individual business units and to hold the managers of those individual businesses accountable for performance. Spinoffs from conglomerates are generally more focused, and offer investors greater transparency while giving management teams a clearer path to unlock the value in their business.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;
			&lt;strong&gt;Loud voices. &lt;/strong&gt;We live in an era of shareholder activism, and many big activist investors have been increasingly vocal in calling for conglomerates to break up. Moreover, deconglomeratization has become a popular and desirable narrative for the broader investing public.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;strong&gt;Timing. &lt;/strong&gt;While we don’t believe this is a primary driver in every situation, the fact remains that we are at a favorable point in the cycle for spinoff activity—valuations are higher, and companies can monetize their assets on good terms (this is especially true for cyclical businesses).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	These factors have combined to drive a number of spinoffs in the industrial sector of late, and in many cases these worked out very well for shareholders. For example, Danaher spun out Fortive in 2016. Danaher retained the company’s life sciences, diagnostics, dental, water quality, and product ID segments, while the new Fortive included&amp;nbsp;businesses focused on&amp;nbsp;test and measurement, retail fueling, telematics, and automation. As shown in the chart below, the “unified” Danaher was valued at $70 billion as of this spinoff transaction; the two entities combined were worth nearly $100 billion two years later. (Note that&amp;nbsp;Danaher continues to explore spinoff opportunities; it recently announced its intention to carve out its dental business&amp;nbsp;segment into an independent publicly traded company). In another example, Babcock &amp;amp; Wilcox Enterprises, Inc. spun out its power generation business in 2015. The spinoff retained the Babcock &amp;amp; Wilcox name; the remaining company, BWX Technologies, is a service-focused entity focused on government and nuclear operations. This transaction helped drive more than a 500% return for shareholders over two years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyLine&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
	Recent Spinoffs: Mix of Good and Bad Results (Valuations expressed in $ billions)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot; class=&quot;responsiveImg&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.brownadvisory.com/sites/default/files/u1/recent_spinoffs_chart3.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Recent Spinoffs: Mix of Good and Bad Results (Valuations expressed in $ billions)&quot; src=&quot;http://www.brownadvisory.com/sites/default/files/u1/recent_spinoffs_chart3.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 790px; height: 488px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyLine&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	However, not all spinoffs are created equal, and investors should not assume that every breakup of a conglomerate will automatically unlock value. Companies have an enormous amount of flexibility to include or exclude nearly anything they want in a spinoff deal—the business being offered may be loaded up with leverage (from the business being spun off as well as from other businesses in the conglomerate’s portfolio),&amp;nbsp;outsized pension liabilities, environmental liabilities and so forth. Truly awful deals are unlikely in today’s market, as a noxious combination of assets would not pass muster with investors, but it is important to understand the pros and cons of a spun-off entity, so you can make an educated judgment as to just how much value the deal can unlock. For example, in 2015 General Electric spun off its credit card business, Synchrony Financial, and while this spinoff was part of a more complex series of transactions surrounding the disposition of GE Capital assets, there is no question that two years later, GE and Synchrony together were valued at a far lower level than GE had been pre-spin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	When it comes to investing in spinoffs, the overall historical data is positive. The Bloomberg Spinoff Index (a market-cap weighted index that&amp;nbsp;adds spun off companies valued at $1 billion or greater at the time of the spinoff transaction, and hold them&amp;nbsp;for three years after the transaction takes place) is one way to track the returns from these companies. As shown in the chart below, this index has outperformed the S&amp;amp;P 500&lt;sup&gt;®&lt;/sup&gt; Index by a wide margin over time. Investors can’t really duplicate the experience of this index, and it is probably not prudent to expect this sort of performance advantage to persist as a universal truth forever. We prefer a more precise approach—in other words, we want to selectively invest in higher-quality spinoffs while avoiding the less attractive ones. As always, we believe that it is essential to understand the underlying business fundamentals of a given company, and the terms of the specific spinoff being contemplated, so we can make educated decisions. We look forward to diving into the research on a variety of proposed industrial spinoffs—from GE and other firms—as more details emerge about them.&amp;nbsp;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/sites/default/files/u1/b-box-logo.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 12px; height: 16px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyLine&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
	Cumulative Return, 6/30/03-6/30/18:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot; style=&quot;font-size: 1em;&quot;&gt;
	Bloomberg U.S. Spinoff Index vs. S&amp;amp;P 500 Index&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot; class=&quot;responsiveImg&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.brownadvisory.com/sites/default/files/u1/15_spinoff_return.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Cumulative Return, 6/30/03-6/30/18: Bloomberg U.S. Spinoff Index vs. S&amp;amp;P 500 Index&quot; src=&quot;/sites/default/files/u1/15_spinoff_return.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 790px; height: 402px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 14px; font-size: 0.8em;&quot;&gt;
	Source: Bloomberg.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyLine&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	The views expressed are those of Brown Advisory as of the date referenced and are subject to change at any time based on market or other conditions. These views are not intended to be and should not be relied upon as investment advice and are not intended to be a forecast of future events or a guarantee of future results. Past performance is not a guarantee of future performance and you may not get back the amount invested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;padding: 5px 0px 0px; line-height: 1.5em; font-size: 0.7em;&quot;&gt;
	The information provided in this material is not intended to be and should not be considered to be a recommendation or suggestion to engage in or refrain from a particular course of action or to make or hold a particular investment or pursue a particular investment strategy, including whether or not to buy, sell, or hold any of the securities or asset classes mentioned. It should not be assumed that investments in such securities or asset classes have been or will be profitable. To the extent specific securities are mentioned, they have been selected by the author on an objective basis to illustrate views expressed in the commentary and do not represent all of the securities purchased, sold or recommended for advisory clients. The information contained herein has been prepared from sources believed reliable but is not guaranteed by us as to its timeliness or accuracy, and is not a complete summary or statement of all available data. This piece is intended solely for our clients and prospective clients, is for informational purposes only, and is not individually tailored for or directed to any particular client or prospective client.&lt;br /&gt;
	&lt;br /&gt;
	The S&amp;amp;P 500® Index represents the large-cap segment of the U.S. equity markets and consists of approximately 500 leading companies in leading industries of the U.S. economy. Criteria evaluated include market capitalization, financial viability, liquidity, public float, sector representation and corporate structure. An index constituent must also be considered a U.S. company. Standard &amp;amp; Poor’s, S&amp;amp;P®, and S&amp;amp;P 500® are registered trademarks of Standard &amp;amp; Poor’s Financial Services LLC (“S&amp;amp;P”), a subsidiary of S&amp;amp;P Global Inc.&lt;br /&gt;
	&lt;br /&gt;
	The Bloomberg US Spin-Off Index is a modified market-capitalization weighted index that contains equities over USD 1 billion that were spun-off from the US companies. The index includes companies from spin-off, split-off and carved out activities, and does not include the companies offered as tracking stock or in-specie.&lt;br /&gt;
	BLOOMBERG and BLOOMBERG INDICES are trademarks or service marks of Bloomberg Finance L.P. Bloomberg Finance L.P. and its affiliates (&quot;collectively, &quot;Bloomberg&quot;) or Bloomberg&#039;s licensors own all proprietary right in the BLOOMBERG INDICES.&lt;br /&gt;
	BLOOMBERG, BLOOMBERG PROFESSIONAL, BLOOMBERG MARKETS, BLOOMBERG NEWS,BLOOMBERG ANYWHERE, BLOOMBERG TRADEBOOK, BLOOMBERG BONDTRADER, BLOOMBERG TELEVISION, BLOOMBERG RADIO, BLOOMBERG PRESS, BLOOMBERG.COM and BLOOMBERG LAW are trademarks and service marks of Bloomberg Finance L.P., a Delaware limited partnership, or its subsidiaries&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     <pubDate>Wednesday, August 8, 2018 - 10:00</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Adi Padva, Simon Paterson, CFA</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">&lt;a href=&quot;/en/theadvisory/spin-city-new-wave-deconglomeratization&quot;&gt;24531&lt;/a&gt;</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>&lt;a href=&quot;/en/en/theadvisory/capital-conservation&quot;&gt;Capital Conservation&lt;/a&gt;</title>
    <link>/en/en/theadvisory/capital-conservation</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;
	“Sustainable investing” means different things to different people. Some sustainable investors want to make a positive impact on the world, others want to align their portfolio with a specific mission or set of values, and still others simply want to screen out businesses and behaviors from the portfolio that they find objectionable. None of these goals are “right” or “wrong,” and those who work in sustainable investing generally embrace the different goals, viewpoints and methodologies that have evolved over the years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	In our work managing Brown Advisory’s Large-Cap Sustainable Growth strategy, sustainable investing is first and foremost about performance. For nearly a decade, we have combined fundamental and sustainable research to build a portfolio that has outperformed its benchmark, the Russell 1000&lt;sup&gt;®&lt;/sup&gt; Growth Index. Our &lt;i&gt;risk-adjusted&lt;/i&gt; results are particularly important to us, and as of June 30, 2018, the strategy’s annualized alpha and Sharpe ratio (two commonly cited measures of risk-adjusted performance) since inception were both ranked in the top 4% of eVestment’s large-growth manager universe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;strong&gt;A major driver of our performance has been our consistent ability to perform well during down markets.&lt;/strong&gt; Over the last five years, we achieved down-market capture of just 84%; this ratio measures the strategy’s return vs. its benchmark during periods of market decline. That result places us among the top 5% of our large-growth peers, according to eVestment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Many investors are concerned about the aging bull market, and as a result want to understand how their investments might perform in a downturn. We are not making a prediction about the market’s near-term path, but we believe that our holdings can weather a downturn relatively well. &lt;strong&gt;Our experience has taught us that there is a strong link between the sustainable characteristics of our portfolio companies, and their resilience during difficult market periods.&lt;/strong&gt; Here, we will discuss some of the reasons why we think that link is so strong, and provide a number of examples of portfolio companies whose sustainable business models have directly contributed to their strength in declining markets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 style=&quot;color:#005ea1;&quot;&gt;
	Sustainable Investing and Downside Protection&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/sites/default/files/u1/capital_coservation_thumb.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 350px; height: 195px; float: right;padding-left:10px;&quot; /&gt;Every sustainable business is somewhat unique, but we tend to look for a variety of factors that, in our view, contribute to steady, consistent growth and profitability in both healthy and challenging markets. We cover three of these factors below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Companies that offer their customers a compelling “sustainable return on investment.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Many of our portfolio companies help their customers address sustainability challenges like climate risk, energy reliability, water management, commodity price volatility and many other issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	These businesses often hold up well in down markets. One reason is that many sustainability challenges represent real and meaningful costs: Energy costs money, materials cost money, and, increasingly, water and its use cost money. Many of our portfolio companies help their customers save money in these areas. This tends to foster strong customer retention—even during low points in the business cycle when these customers are looking for ways to cut spending.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	A good example is Ecolab, which offers water, energy and sanitation solutions to customers in many different sectors of the economy. In 2016 alone, Ecolab reported that it had helped customers conserve 161 billion gallons of water, 52 million pounds of waste, and 11 trillion BTUs of energy. Because it delivers clear and measurable payback to its customers, Ecolab has generally navigated tougher periods without losing much business. Coming out of the global financial crisis, the company’s revenue declined only 4% in 2009, and it was able to improve its gross margins and EBIT during that period. In the years after the recession, Ecolab delivered double-digit top-line growth. Its revenue mix includes a healthy base of consumables that generate recurring revenue, which contributes to its revenue visibility and stability from year to year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Danaher’s environmental businesses offer similar “sustainable ROI” to clients—helping customers to reduce operating costs, materials waste, and environmental impact—and these businesses also held up well in the wake of the credit crisis. Danaher’s overall business suffered double-digit year-over-year declines in all four quarters of 2009, but its environmental portfolio held relatively steady, and several of its water treatment businesses generated positive growth. Danaher’s environmental businesses gradually have become a more meaningful part of the company’s diverse business mix, especially after its recent acquisition of Pall Corp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Companies that use sustainability to build supply chain advantages.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; As companies mature and gain leadership in their markets, supply chain mastery becomes critical to their efforts to improve or even maintain their margins. A number of our companies use sustainable thinking as they select suppliers, and go several steps further, developing clear operational standards rooted in sustainability and then helping their suppliers achieve those standards. By cementing their vendor relationships in this manner, companies can make their supply chains more reliable, reduce the volatility of their costs, and, in some cases, enhance their overall brand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;quote&quot; style=&quot;padding:15px;&quot;&gt;
	Over time, we have seen a strong link between the sustainable characteristics of companies and the resilience of their stock prices during down markets.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Companies that use sustainability to inform long-term capital allocation decisions.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Every management team claims a long-term focus, yet many run their businesses with a “don’t fix what isn’t broken” mentality and avoid taking the bold steps that could redirect capital toward a more profitable path. Environmental and social challenges are creating huge markets all over the world, and we have been attracted to a number of companies based on their smart and substantial investments to embrace those markets. Of course, our evaluation of a company’s strategy is based on many different factors, but we take note when companies link capital allocation to opportunities stemming from long-term, sustainable trends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Shifting capital from a mature business to a newer opportunity may seem riskier than standing pat. But we find that companies that make these decisions wisely are the ones that are built to last. Conversely, there is often a good deal of embedded downside risk in a company that remains focused on declining industries that face slowing growth, shrinking margins or competitive disruption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	A. O. Smith is a prime example of a firm whose capital allocation decisions consistently loop back to sustainable, long-term thinking. The company had a lot of foresight regarding rising middle-class populations that need hot, clean water; this opportunity motivated the sale of its electric motor business (which produced roughly one-third of company revenue at the time), so it could focus on its water treatment product lines. We believe that the company’s growth would have been much slower in recent years if it had retained its motor business. A. O. Smith has invested strategically in China for more than 20 years, seeking to serve China’s burgeoning middle class with solutions for water safety and comfort. It now generates more than 30% of its revenue in China; its share of the Chinese water heater market has grown from 10% to 25% in the past decade, and it owns a 20% share of the Chinese water purifier market as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 style=&quot;color:#005ea1;&quot;&gt;
	The Bottom Line: Sustainable = Resilient&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	As noted earlier, investing in companies with these sustainable characteristics has helped us generate top-decile risk-adjusted returns and down-market capture. Of course, other factors have contributed to these results as well: We are disciplined about capping exposure to any single company, we emphasize consistency of growth over absolute growth rates, and we proactively optimize position sizes across the portfolio as prices change and conditions for each portfolio company evolve. In our view, all of these factors have helped our portfolio hold up relatively well when the market has stumbled.&amp;nbsp;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/sites/default/files/u1/b-box-logo.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 12px; height: 16px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyLine&quot;&gt;
	&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	The views expressed are those of the author and Brown Advisory as of the date referenced and are subject to change at any time based on market or other conditions. These views are not intended to be and should not be relied upon as investment advice and are not intended to be a forecast of future events or a guarantee of future results. Past performance is not a guarantee of future performance and you may not get back the amount invested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;font-size:.7em;line-height:1.5em;padding:5px 0 0 0;&quot;&gt;
	The information provided in this material is not intended to be and should not be considered to be a recommendation or suggestion to engage in or refrain from a particular course of action or to make or hold a particular investment or pursue a particular investment strategy, including whether or not to buy, sell, or hold any of the securities or asset classes mentioned. It should not be assumed that investments in such securities or asset classes have been or will be profitable. To the extent specific securities are mentioned, they have been selected by the author on an objective basis to illustrate views expressed in the commentary and do not represent all of the securities purchased, sold or recommended for advisory clients. The information contained herein has been prepared from sources believed reliable but is not guaranteed by us as to its timeliness or accuracy, and is not a complete summary or statement of all available data. This piece is intended solely for our clients and prospective clients, is for informational purposes only, and is not individually tailored for or directed to any particular client or prospective client. Private investments mentioned in this article may only be available for qualified purchasers and accredited investors. All charts, economic and market forecasts presented herein are for illustrative purposes only. Note that this data does not represent any Brown Advisory investment offerings.&lt;br /&gt;
	&lt;br /&gt;
	The eVestment U.S. Large-Cap Growth Equity universe classification (“universe”) includes U.S. equity strategies that invest primarily in large capitalization stocks with fundamental growth characteristics or products that invest in growth stocks/sectors. The expected benchmarks for this universe would include the Russell 1000®, or S&amp;amp;P 500. Managers in this category will typically indicate a “Primary Capitalization Emphasis” equal to Large-Cap and a “Primary Style Emphasis” equal to Growth. The minimum criteria necessary for inclusion in an eVestment Universe are 1) minimum of one year of performance history, and 2) updated portfolio characteristics for the product. All products meeting the criteria are evaluated for inclusion. Managers voluntarily populate performance data into the database for inclusion, and the number of managers in each period consists only of managers that provided that data point and were in the universe for that entire period. For example, the number of managers that provided turnover and active share statistics as of 12/31/2011 differed from 262 to 25, respectively, despite representing the same eVestment U.S. large-cap growth equity universe. Historical manager data for active share, which has become more widely used since 2009, is notably limited prior to 2014.&lt;br /&gt;
	&lt;br /&gt;
	&lt;strong&gt;Return on Investment (ROI)&lt;/strong&gt; is the ratio between the net profit and cost of investment resulting from an investment of some resource. A high ROI means the investment’s gains compare favorably to its cost.&lt;br /&gt;
	&lt;br /&gt;
	The &lt;strong&gt;Russell 1000® Growth Index&lt;/strong&gt; measures the performance of the large-cap growth segment of the U.S. equity universe. It includes those Russell 1000® Index companies with higher price-to-book ratios and higher forecasted growth values. The Russell 1000® Growth Index is constructed to provide a comprehensive and unbiased barometer for the large-cap growth segment. The Index is completely reconstituted annually to ensure new and growing equities are included and that the represented companies continue to reflect growth characteristics.&lt;br /&gt;
	&lt;br /&gt;
	“FTSE®”, “Russell®”, “MTS®”, “FTSE TMX®” and “FTSE Russell” and other service marks and trademarks related to the FTSE or Russell indexes are trademarks of the London Stock Exchange Group companies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     <pubDate>Tuesday, August 7, 2018 - 09:57</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Karina Funk, CFA, David Powell, CFA</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">&lt;a href=&quot;/en/theadvisory/capital-conservation&quot;&gt;24511&lt;/a&gt;</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>&lt;a href=&quot;/en/en/theadvisory/investment-perspectives-managing-risk&quot;&gt;Investment Perspectives | Managing Risk&lt;/a&gt;</title>
    <link>/en/en/theadvisory/investment-perspectives-managing-risk</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;
	In 1963, Bob Dylan warned us that the times, they are a-changin’—and while he wasn’t talking about capital markets, his words ring as true today for investors as they did for those growing up in the turbulent &#039;60s. Market conditions may indeed be changing, and in ways that warrant a reassessment of portfolio positioning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	We tend to be strategic rather than tactical in our approach to investing, but a combination of recent fundamental developments and valuation changes has caused us to add a note of caution in conversations with clients and in the management of their portfolios. In essence, we think bonds are becoming increasingly attractive on a risk/reward basis, while stocks may be getting less so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Just to be clear, this is not a sudden or abrupt shift in our thinking. We simply want to be sure that clients are aware of the incremental risk we have observed in the investing environment over the last 18-24 months. From an economic perspective, growth in the U.S. continues apace and has even accelerated somewhat, thanks in part to the corporate tax reductions enacted late last year. At the same time, the current expansion, now about nine years old, is among the longest on record. Although there are few signs of recession on the horizon, it’s inevitable that one will occur at some point. Cycles have yet to be eradicated from the economic landscape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;
	Incremental Equity Risks&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Several evolving dynamics in the stock market, when taken together, suggest that risk levels have increased a bit over the last year or so:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;one-column-list&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;strong&gt;&lt;i&gt;Valuations:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; To state the obvious, stock prices gained considerable ground during 2017 and are slightly higher so far in 2018. Even as the “E” (earnings) component of the P/E ratio has increased in 2018 thanks to the strong economy and tax cuts, the “P” (price) component has moved up more, and valuations have risen perceptibly. The S&amp;amp;P 500&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10px;&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;®&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt; Index is now priced at about 17 times forward 12 months’ estimated earnings. While this valuation level is nowhere near the extremes of recent bull market peaks, it is 5-10% above long-term historical averages. Using price/cash flow as a measure, valuations are more like 20% higher than normal.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;strong&gt;&lt;i&gt;Concentration:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Much of the U.S. equity market’s gain since early 2017 has been concentrated in a relatively small number of sectors and specific stocks. In general, growth stocks have meaningfully outperformed the rest of the market, and technology stocks in particular have led the way. In the 18 months ending June 30, 2018, the Russell 1000&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10px;&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;®&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt; Growth Index rose 39.7%, compared to the Russell 1000&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10px;&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;®&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt; Value Index’s increase of 11.7%. The well-publicized FAANG&amp;nbsp;stocks (Facebook, Apple, Amazon, Netflix and Google’s parent company, Alphabet) have accounted for a remarkable 30.6% of the gain in the Russell 1000 Growth Index over this same time period.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;strong&gt;&lt;i&gt;Correlations:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Less widely recognized has been the reduced tendency of stocks to move together—a behavior known as correlation. For much of the current bull market’s history, the spread between the best- and worst-performing sectors was comparatively narrow, but in more recent times, this pattern has shifted. In the first six months of this year, for example, technology stocks as a group gained 10.9%, while the telecommunications sector was down 8.4%. Taking a more granular look at subsectors, internet retail stocks were up 48.2%, while packaged foods dropped 10.9%.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	More broadly, global crosscurrents are clouding the outlook and adding to uncertainty. Central banks across the globe are in various stages of withdrawing monetary support after many years of reflating. International trade, long a positive influence on growth, is now being threatened by the imposition of tariffs around the world. Labor markets in the U.S. are surprisingly tight, yet wages have not yet risen sufficiently to cause consumer spending to accelerate markedly. Oil prices are up sharply in the last year and have roughly doubled from their lows of two years ago, but many other commodities are closer to their 52-week lows than their highs. Although largely subdued of late, inflation lurks as a potential disrupter to growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyLine&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
	Exhibit 1: U.S. Treasury Yield Curves Over Time&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot; style=&quot;font-size: 1em;&quot;&gt;
	Federal Reserve rate hikes shifted yields higher and flattened the curve.&lt;!--9--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot; class=&quot;responsiveImg&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.brownadvisory.com/sites/default/files/u1/ip_exhibit1_yieldcurves.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Exhibit 1: U.S. Treasury Yield Curves Over Time&quot; src=&quot;/sites/default/files/u1/ip_exhibit1_yieldcurves.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 800px; height: 390px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 0.8em; line-height: 14px;&quot;&gt;
	Source: Bloomberg.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyLine&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	In spite of what some would argue is an atmosphere of increasingly elevated risk, many investors are stretching for incremental returns by adding to positions in the most richly valued stocks&amp;nbsp;or in illiquid investments in asset classes with inflated valuations. Adding risk to portfolios at this stage in the economic cycle does not seem like a prudent strategy to us. Rather than making larger equity bets, investors in hedge funds, who tend to be among the most sophisticated institutional and private clients, are deliberately reducing their exposure to equity “beta” or volatility. Traditional long/short equity funds have seen redemptions in recent months, while credit and event-driven funds (whose returns are largely independent of the equity markets) have seen meaningful inflows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;
	Opportunity to Rebalance?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	It’s anyone’s guess as to how equity markets will perform over the next year or two, but as the bull market ages, we think it makes sense to start dialing back portfolio risk levels. A primary mechanism for managing risk is rebalancing, with particular focus on the role of bonds in the portfolio. Without intending to forecast, it seems only sensible to assume that equity market returns over the next several years are unlikely to be as robust as they’ve been during the long bull market, or that they will equal their long-term historical average of 8-10%. Our working assumption in constructing portfolios today is 6-7%. (Let’s hope we’re wrong, but we prefer to be surprised on the upside.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	At the same time, with rising interest rates, bond returns are increasingly compelling. While the role of bonds since the financial crisis of 2008-09 has been more about reducing portfolio risk and less about producing incremental profit (although returns have generally been positive), that role may be changing in favor of relative returns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	In the U.S., bond yields are still below average historical levels, but they are well above post-recession lows and gradually rising. To gain a sense of where yields could go over time, it can be useful to look at very long-term trends. A December 2017 working paper of the National Bureau of Economic Research examines the rates of return between 1870 and 2015&amp;nbsp;in several asset classes across 16 developed economies. Based on this very broad data set, the real return for bonds (i.e., return net of inflation) was slightly more than 2% and for equities was just under 7%. Using the 10-year U.S. Treasury bond (currently yielding about 3%) as a barometer and assuming inflation at roughly 2% in today’s economy, the real return is about 1%. A portfolio that includes bonds of varying quality and duration (such as the Brown Advisory Core Fixed Income Strategy) can yield more like 4% without compromising meaningfully on quality. While real returns in the 1-2% range are still low relative to the past, they have been slowly rising and, importantly, are meaningfully higher than the real yields in most other developed nations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Based on its own statements, the Fed is intent on raising interest rates to head off what it sees as a threat of higher inflation, given tight labor markets and a rise in certain input costs. In addition, restoring rates to more “normal” levels would give it room to once again reduce rates as a strategy to stimulate the economy when the next recession occurs. If the Fed continues along this path (and futures markets suggest that investors believe it will), short-term rates will trend higher. Long-term rates, however, remain low by historical standards. It’s not totally clear why this is the case, but it tends to suggest that bond investors are wary of a slowdown in the economy despite rather strong economic indicators. Further, the supply of long-duration instruments is also artificially low, as the Fed has a huge portfolio that it purchased during the recession in order to stave off the crisis. As it unwinds that position over time, the prices of long-dated bonds could be pressured by incremental supply, sending their yields higher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	The result of this combination of factors is that the yield curve for taxable bonds is almost “flat”—that is, there is relatively little difference between short- and long-term interest rates. (In municipal bonds, the yield curve is steeper.) Using U.S. Treasury obligations as a gauge, the difference in yield, or “spread,” between a two-year and a 30-year bond is roughly 40 basis points (a basis point is one one-hundredth of a percent) and between a 10-year and 30-year bond the spread is only about 10&amp;nbsp;basis points. When long rates fall below short-term ones, the yield curve is said to be “inverted”—a condition that typically occurs in weak economic circumstances. According to research by the San Francisco Fed, an inverted yield curve has preceded every one of the nine recessions that have occurred since 1955, with only one false positive reading during that period. Although the curve is not inverted now, some observers are concerned that it may invert soon, thereby signaling that a recession may be on the horizon. The potential for inversion is not a reason in and of itself to make changes in asset allocation, but the combination of higher short-term yields and additional equity market uncertainty does affect our thinking about portfolio positioning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;
	Risks in Bonds&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	In attempting to reduce portfolio risk by shifting assets from equities to bonds, it’s important to recognize that bonds carry risks of their own. At this stage of the economic cycle, a primary concern on most investors’ minds is the prospect of rising interest rates, which would be a negative for all but the shortest-duration bonds. As the cycle matures and the labor market continues to tighten, inflation is becoming an increasingly likely possibility, one that the Fed takes very seriously. Beyond the U.S., central banks around the world are also in various stages of withdrawing stimulus as their respective countries or regions show signs of recovering on their own. Largely because the U.S. recovery is more advanced than the rest of the developed world, interest rates here are higher, but others are catching up. Many non-U.S. investors currently find our rates more attractive than their own and have shifted some of their funds into U.S. bonds. In addition, last year’s tax overhaul resulted in the repatriation of substantial cash balances held abroad by a number of large U.S. corporations. These sources of demand have had the effect of strengthening the dollar&amp;nbsp;but have also kept U.S. bond prices higher and interest rates lower than they might otherwise have been. If this trade becomes less advantageous because of rising rates abroad, it could cause our interest rates to edge higher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	The prospect of rates rising higher causes us to manage bond portfolios a bit differently. For example, we are emphasizing strategies consistent with low durations in large part by utilizing floating-rate bonds or bonds that return principal quickly. By doing this, we have more opportunity to reap the benefits of higher rates without suffering undue price erosion. (Variable-rate bonds are less volatile in price than fixed-rate ones because their yield, rather than price, adjusts to reflect changes in the interest rate environment.) In any case, it’s important to recognize that yield is a more important driver of bond returns than price. Over time, a bond’s income stream more than offsets any erosion of principal that results from the negative impact of rising rates. Because of this, bonds have produced positive returns since 2013—a period in which interest rates have broadly doubled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	The second major risk in today’s bond markets is the possibility of default if economic conditions worsen. In recent years, companies have added considerably to their debt burdens, in the interest of deploying capital efficiently (sometimes at the urging of activist shareholders) and because interest expense is still tax-deductible. The result has been a growing number of bonds rated as “junk” by various rating agencies. States and municipalities have also taken on more debt. Even within the investment-grade category, bond ratings have declined over the last several years as financial leverage has generally risen. As an indication, the percentage of corporate bonds rated BBB has grown from 29% in 2000 to 53% today, according to Bloomberg. Another measure of risk is the spread between the yield on corporate debt (including high-yield or “junk” debt) and treasury bonds (considered “riskless”) of the same maturity. Again, that spread is currently at multiyear lows, meaning that investors are getting paid less for the risk they are taking in various types of bonds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;
	Managing Bond Risk&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	The risks of rising rates and a higher incidence of defaults can be managed. As noted, we like to keep maturities relatively short or invest in variable-rate bonds in order to avoid the volatility that comes from changes in the interest rate environment. Default risks can also be managed through the use of fundamentally based credit research. Because of the large number of taxable and nontaxable bond issues, bonds tend to be less intensely researched than stocks. As a result, our analysts are able to identify opportunities to take advantage of inefficiencies in the market, capturing incremental yield without taking on commensurate fundamental risk. Adding mispriced, lower-rated bonds to a portfolio can produce incremental yield and total return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyLine&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
	Exhibit 2: U.S. Bond Returns Since 2013&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot; style=&quot;font-size: 1em; line-height: 18px;&quot;&gt;
	Despite rates rising significantly since 2013, bonds have produced solidly positive returns.&lt;br /&gt;
	Annualized Returns, 04/30/2013-06/30/2018&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot; class=&quot;responsiveImg&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.brownadvisory.com/sites/default/files/u1/ip_exhibit2_bondreturns.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Exhibit 2: U.S. Bond Returns Since 2013&quot; src=&quot;/sites/default/files/u1/ip_exhibit2_bondreturns.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 800px; height: 286px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 0.8em; line-height: 14px;&quot;&gt;
	Source: Bloomberg, using ICE BofAML Benchmarks. ICE BofAML US Broad Market Index for U.S. Aggregate. ICE BofAML US Treasury &amp;amp; Agency Index for Treasuries. ICE BofAML US High Yield Index for High Yield. ICE BofAML US Municipal Securities Index for Municipals. *Note: Returns do not take into account the impact of taxes on taxable bond returns with the exception of municipals, which are tax-exempt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyLine&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	The second approach to mitigating overall portfolio risk is one that we advocate as an ongoing strategy: keeping ample cash on hand to meet the need for withdrawals from the portfolio, whether for living expenses or some other purpose. The amount of cash and number of years of spending varies according to individual circumstances, but clients should never be forced to sell assets at depressed prices to meet cash needs. We see this period in the markets as a particularly good time to review the need for liquidity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	In summary, the combination of rising equity valuations and increasingly attractive bond yields has created a timely opportunity to re-examine asset allocation. Although the long-term outlook for stocks hasn’t changed, it’s been a long time since fixed income returns have been as competitive with equities as they are today, to say nothing of the generally lower risks associated with bonds. It’s important to note here that we’re not recommending wholesale changes in asset allocation. We are not market timers and have no particular insight into near-term movements in the markets. We are, however, suggesting a review of portfolio positioning and adjustments at the margin where it makes sense. And, as always, maintaining sufficient liquidity is the key to allowing portfolios to withstand volatility in the markets, whenever it occurs.&amp;nbsp;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/sites/default/files/u1/b-box-logo.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 12px; height: 16px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyLine&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	The views expressed are those of Brown Advisory as of the date referenced and are subject to change at any time based on market or other conditions. These views are not intended to be and should not be relied upon as investment advice and are not intended to be a forecast of future events or a guarantee of future results. Past performance is not a guarantee of future performance and you may not get back the amount invested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;padding: 5px 0px 0px; line-height: 1.5em; font-size: 0.7em;&quot;&gt;
	The information provided in this material is not intended to be and should not be considered to be a recommendation or suggestion to engage in or refrain from a particular course of action or to make or hold a particular investment or pursue a particular investment strategy, including whether or not to buy, sell, or hold any of the securities or asset classes mentioned. It should not be assumed that investments in such securities or asset classes have been or will be profitable. To the extent specific securities are mentioned, they have been selected by the author on an objective basis to illustrate views expressed in the commentary and do not represent all of the securities purchased, sold or recommended for advisory clients. The information contained herein has been prepared from sources believed reliable but is not guaranteed by us as to its timeliness or accuracy, and is not a complete summary or statement of all available data. This piece is intended solely for our clients and prospective clients, is for informational purposes only, and is not individually tailored for or directed to any particular client or prospective client. The Russell 1000® Growth Index measures the performance of the large-cap growth segment of the U.S. equity universe. It includes those Russell 1000® Index companies with higher price-to-book ratios and higher forecasted growth values. The Russell 1000® Growth Index is constructed to provide a comprehensive and unbiased barometer for the large-cap growth segment. The Index is completely reconstituted annually to ensure new and growing equities are included and that the represented companies continue to reflect growth characteristics. The Russell 1000® Value Index is constructed to provide a comprehensive and unbiased barometer for the large-cap value segment. The Index is completely reconstituted annually to ensure new and growing equities are included and that the represented companies continue to reflect value characteristics. Russell 2000®, Russell 1000® Growth, Russell 1000®, Russell 1000® Value, Russell 2000® Growth, Russell 2000® Value, Russell 3000®, Russell 1000® Pure Value and Russell 1000® Pure Growth when related to the Russell indexes are trademarks of the . RussellLondon Stock Exchange Group of companies.&lt;br /&gt;
	The S&amp;amp;P 500® Index represents the large-cap segment of the U.S. equity markets and consists of approximately 500 leading companies in leading industries of the U.S. economy. Criteria evaluated include market capitalization, financial viability, liquidity, public float, sector representation and corporate structure. An index constituent must also be considered a U.S. company. Standard &amp;amp; Poor’s, S&amp;amp;P®, and S&amp;amp;P 500® are registered trademarks of Standard &amp;amp; Poor’s Financial Services LLC (“S&amp;amp;P”), a subsidiary of S&amp;amp;P Global Inc.&lt;br /&gt;
	The ICE BofAML US Broad Market Index tracks the performance of US dollar denominated investment grade debt publicly issued in the US domestic market, including US Treasury, quasi-government, corporate, securitized and collateralized securities. With the exception of local currency sovereign debt, qualifying securities must have an investment grade rating (based on an average of Moody’s, S&amp;amp;P and Fitch). The ICE BofAML US Treasury &amp;amp; Agency Index tracks the performance of US dollar denominated US Treasury and non-subordinated US agency debt issued in the US domestic market. Qualifying securities must have an investment grade rating (based on an average of Moody’s, S&amp;amp;P and Fitch). The ICE BofAML US High Yield Index tracks the performance of US dollar denominated below investment grade corporate debt publicly issued in the US domestic market. Qualifying securities must have a below investment grade rating (based on an average of Moody’s, S&amp;amp;P and Fitch), at least 18 months to final maturity at the time of issuance, at least one year remaining term to final maturity as of the rebalancing date, a fixed coupon schedule and a minimum amount outstanding of $250 million. The ICE BofAML US Municipal Securities Index tracks the performance of US dollar denominated investment grade tax-exempt debt publicly issued by US states and territories, and their political subdivisions, in the US domestic market. Qualifying securities must have at least one year remaining term to final maturity, at least 18 months to final maturity at the time of issuance, a fixed coupon schedule and an investment grade rating (based on an average of Moody’s, S&amp;amp;P and Fitch). Intercontinental Exchange, Inc. (NYSE:ICE) operates a leading network of exchanges and clearing houses. ICE’s exchanges and clearing houses, which include the New York Stock Exchange, serve global commodity and financial futures and equities markets. The New York Stock Exchange is the world leader in capital raising and equities trading. ICE is a leading provider of data services across global markets. Trademarks of ICE and/or its affiliates include Intercontinental Exchange, ICE, ICE block design, NYSE, New York Stock Exchange, Interactive Data and Trayport. BLOOMBERG is a trademark and service mark of Bloomberg Finance L.P.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     <pubDate>Wednesday, August 1, 2018 - 11:40</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Bill Paternotte, CFA</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">&lt;a href=&quot;/en/theadvisory/investment-perspectives-managing-risk&quot;&gt;24501&lt;/a&gt;</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>&lt;a href=&quot;/en/en/theadvisory/2018-berkshire-hathaway-annual-shareholder-meeting&quot;&gt;2018 Berkshire Hathaway Annual Shareholder Meeting&lt;/a&gt;</title>
    <link>/en/en/theadvisory/2018-berkshire-hathaway-annual-shareholder-meeting</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;
	Thousands come to Omaha every May for the Berkshire Hathaway Annual Shareholders Meeting to hear the insights of Warren Buffett, chairman of Berkshire since 1965, and his longtime business partner Charles Munger, vice chairman of Berkshire. Rather than a transcript, these notes are filtered observations organized to group common themes from responses to related questions. They do not cover every question and answer, but that is available within a fabulous archive of Berkshire’s annual meetings at &lt;a href=&quot;https://buffett.cnbc.com/&quot;&gt;buffett.cnbc.com&lt;/a&gt;. The archive has complete audio/video and transcripts as well as highlights of past meetings from 1994 through the present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	The format of the meeting is question and answer. Shareholders and investment analysts pose questions to Buffett and Munger in two 2.5-hour sessions covering about 60 questions. They answer in clear-thinking and entertaining ways that keep shareholders coming back year after year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Berkshire Hathaway is one of the larger holdings in the Brown Advisory Flexible Equity Strategy. Buffett and Munger are significant influences on our investment approach. Members of our investment team have attended these annual meetings for over 30 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;
	Berkshire Hathaway&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	In the 53 years since Buffett took control, Berkshire Hathaway has grown from a small, competitively challenged New England textile company to one of the largest U.S. companies, with nearly 400,000 employees and an equity market capitalization of $475 billion. Berkshire is the sixth most valuable company in the U.S. after Apple, Amazon, Alphabet (Google), Microsoft and Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Berkshire is extremely decentralized, with just 26 employees at its corporate offices and the rest at about 90 separate operating companies. Berkshire is unusual among public companies. It doesn’t manage for quarter-to-quarter earnings, provide earnings guidance, or have budgets and strategic plans at the parent company, though some of the subsidiaries do. Major capital allocation decisions are centralized with Buffett and a few others, while operating decisions are made at the subsidiary level by the managers of those businesses. Buffett is almost 88 years old and still going strong, though he has prepared for his succession by naming Ajit Jain to oversee insurance and Greg Abel to oversee the noninsurance businesses. The culture of Berkshire, particularly the attitude toward capital allocation, delegation of managerial authority to business units, fiscal conservatism and treating shareholders as business partners, should outlast Buffett.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Buffett uses the increase in Berkshire’s share price and shareholders’ equity per share as proxies for its growth in intrinsic value. These have compounded at an amazing pace that is almost twice the 9.7% annual return of the Standard &amp;amp; Poor’s 500® Index since Buffett took control in 1965. Even after becoming a large company, Berkshire has continued to compound its value as fast as the U.S. equity market. In the last 10 years (2008 through 2017), Berkshire’s shareholders’ equity per share and share price grew at 10.5% and 7.7% annually, respectively, compared with 8.5% total return for the S&amp;amp;P 500 Index. Berkshire’s book value growth is after tax, while the S&amp;amp;P Index return is pretax. Given Berkshire’s size, it is no longer a stock that will make you rich, but it is a stock that should keep you rich while still providing a good return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Buffett and Munger celebrate good business and investment practices, the potential for human achievement, high ethics and decency to one’s fellow man. Listening to Buffett and Munger, you get a course in business, investing and decision-making drawn from their combined 182 years of life experience. Though Munger says he is running very hard just to stay in place, age does not appear to have slowed either of their intellects. The course is more about how to think than what to think, but whenever I’ve found myself disagreeing with their thinking, I have benefited from rethinking my views. The meeting also serves to ingrain the culture of Berkshire with shareholders and employees. Readers seeking to know more about their approach are encouraged to study Berkshire’s Owner’s Manual and Buffett’s letters to shareholders, available at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.berkshirehathaway.com/&quot;&gt;www.berkshirehathaway.com&lt;/a&gt;; the book &lt;i&gt;Poor Charlie’s Almanack&lt;/i&gt;, a collection of speeches and presentations by Munger; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://buffett.cnbc.com/&quot;&gt;CNBC Buffett Archive&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Berkshire’s largest business is property and casualty insurance, with GEICO being the most recognizable brand among several insurance businesses. Insurance operations in total contributed $60 billion, or about 25% of Berkshire’s $242 billion revenue in 2017. Though insurance produced an unusual underwriting loss in 2017, it provided $114 billion in investable float, which partially funds Berkshire’s $314 billion investment portfolio. Other large or recognized noninsurance businesses within Berkshire are Burlington Northern Railroad, Berkshire Hathaway Energy, Precision Castparts, Fruit of the Loom, Dairy Queen, See’s Candies, Duracell and Clayton Homes. Berkshire’s investment portfolio holds about $186 billion in equities and $118 billion in cash equivalents and bonds as of March 31, 2018. Among the larger equity holdings are Wells Fargo (Berkshire owns 9.9% of the shares outstanding), Kraft Heinz (26.7%), Coca-Cola (9.4%), American Express (17.6%), Bank of America (6.8%) and Apple (4.8%)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;
	Bullish on Investing in America&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/sites/default/files/u1/2018berkshire_thumb.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 350px; height: 195px; float: right;padding-left:10px;&quot; /&gt;Buffett opened the meeting with a discussion of investing illustrated with the details of his very first stock purchase in March 1942. He shared the &lt;i&gt;New York Times&lt;/i&gt; headlines from the period showing how badly World War II was going for the U.S., just three months after the attack on Pearl Harbor that brought the U.S. into the war. Buffett, then age 11 and the precocious son of a stockbroker, put his life savings to that point into three shares of Cities Service preferred at $38.25. The stock had traded as high as $84 within the prior year, but by the end of the day, it was down to $37 and later sank to $27. Having seen Cities Service fall to $27, Buffett sold it as soon as it recovered to $41, only to see it climb to $200 in later years. In 1942, Buffett had not yet discovered Benjamin Graham’s teachings about the market existing to &lt;strong&gt;serve&lt;/strong&gt; the intelligent investor rather than &lt;strong&gt;guide&lt;/strong&gt; him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Buffett then stepped back from that personal experience and asked the audience to imagine if they had put &lt;strong&gt;$10,000 into U.S. stocks in March 1942&lt;/strong&gt;, into the then-equivalent of an S&amp;amp;P 500 Index, how much that would be today? After a pause, he revealed the answer is &lt;strong&gt;$51 million&lt;/strong&gt;, the result of $10,000 compounding at 11.9% annually over 76 years. As he explained, you didn’t have to understand accounting, finance, the Federal Reserve or watch the stock market every day; all you had to do was believe in America and that it would rise above its challenges. That compounding is the power of putting your money into the &lt;strong&gt;productive&lt;/strong&gt; assets of businesses within the American system. He noted that the key question for long-term investors in the general market is how American business will do over an investment lifetime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	In contrast, Buffett cited gold as the asset people often turn to when they are worried about the future, but gold is an &lt;strong&gt;unproductive&lt;/strong&gt; asset, it just sits there doing nothing. Gold doesn’t pay dividends or interest, and doesn’t adapt and change to new developments and opportunities. If you had put $10,000 into gold in 1941, you would have bought 300 ounces of it. The 300 ounces today would be worth about $400,000. Gold, the unproductive asset, delivered less than 1 cent for every dollar delivered by U.S. stocks, the productive asset!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	A questioner, noting Buffett’s belief in the U.S. political and economic system, wondered if the divisions among people had grown in the last 50 years and if Buffett had any words of wisdom to help narrow the political divide. Buffett observed that multiple times in his life, people have felt the divisions were greater than ever. Since he bought his first stock, Buffett has lived under 14 presidents—seven Democrats and seven Republicans. One was assassinated, and one had to resign. In addition to World War II, there were the Cuban missile crisis, recessions, financial panic, and war in the streets in the late 1960s over Vietnam and civil rights. Through it all, America has moved ahead in fits and starts. The U.S. will always have disagreements, and some people will feel the world is coming to an end because one party or another is in power, but the system works. In Buffett’s lifetime, GDP per capita has increased sixfold. As a result, everyone in the room lives better than John D. Rockefeller, the richest man in the world when Buffett was born. Buffett would love to be a baby born in the U.S. today. Munger observed that we tend to view our present politicians as much worse than those in the past because we forget just how awful our past politicians were!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;quote&quot; style=&quot;padding: 15px;&quot;&gt;
	When you buy a productive asset, you can figure what it is worth based on what it produces. With a nonproductive asset, you are counting on someone else to later pay more for it.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	A later question on gender equality prompted Buffett to say one of the reasons he is optimistic about the future is the improvement in opportunities for people to rise based on merit rather than gender, race or inheritance. Munger agreed there has been much improvement in that area and expects it to keep getting better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;
	Succession, Decentralization of Management, Deals&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	On the topic of &lt;strong&gt;succession&lt;/strong&gt;, Buffett was asked if he is now semiretired since he had named Greg Abel and Ajit Jain as vice chairmen to oversee the business managers, and Ted Weschler and Todd Combs are helping him with capital allocation and the investment portfolios. Buffett joked that he had been semiretired for years, and that is catching him at his most active. Buffett added that Abel and Jain are smart, energetic, doing a great job and bring a lot to their jobs but not too much because Berkshire’s culture is to delegate the running of its subsidiaries to the individual managers of each subsidiary. Still, there is a lot to oversee. As for capital allocation, Weschler and Combs together manage about $25 billion for Berkshire, so that still leaves $290 billion in other equities, cash and bonds for Buffett. Weschler and Combs do other projects as well and do it all very well. Buffett sometimes copies their ideas. Munger joked that he has observed Buffett for a long time. Mostly he just sits, reads, thinks and occasionally talks to someone—Buffett is very good at doing nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	A later question was whether his successors would be able to access the same sort of deals that Buffett has been able to get on distressed situations in the past. Buffett replied that the parties on the other side calling for money aren’t going to care much whether it is Buffett or someone else on the line—they need the money. Buffett said he probably could have gotten even better terms than he offered on some of them, but setting the terms is a balancing act between getting a great return for Berkshire and not sowing further panic around the seller. Some transactions are coming through Weschler and Combs already.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	To a deal-related question, Buffett said there is nothing fundamentally wrong with &lt;strong&gt;activist investing&lt;/strong&gt; or making hostile offers for businesses, but Berkshire doesn’t do it. Buffett and Munger enjoy being liked by the managers of the businesses Berkshire buys. These managers are the people Berkshire is counting on to run these businesses! Munger said he doesn’t envy the people who go around making hostile offers. Imagine doing that after you’re rich already—it’s insane.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Another question related to &lt;strong&gt;succession&lt;/strong&gt; was how involved Buffett is in subsidiary decisions, noting that Buffett used to be personally involved in setting prices for See’s Candies. Buffett confirmed that was once the case but has not been for a long while. Buffett speaks often with Ajit Jain about insurance pricing for specialized contracts, but other managers less so. He cited a manager of one of their most successful subsidiaries that he talked with probably three times in 10 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Asked to provide examples of &lt;strong&gt;compensation agreements&lt;/strong&gt; with subsidiary managers, Buffett said that Berkshire has kept nearly 100% of the managers it wanted to keep over the years. Managers like making their own decisions, doing a good job and getting recognized for it. Compensation is part but not the whole part of keeping them. There isn’t a single precise formula given all the differences in Berkshire’s businesses. Buffett makes all these decisions personally, and Berkshire doesn’t use compensation consultants. Munger interjected, perhaps to cut Buffett off, that it is to Berkshire’s advantage to keep their compensation arrangements private. Buffett then joked that they do publish what their directors are paid (which is practically nothing).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	When asked &lt;strong&gt;what Berkshire will look like in 50 years&lt;/strong&gt;, Buffett said that he doesn’t know, and he didn’t know 50 years ago what it would look like now. (Berkshire doesn’t do strategic plans.) The people and the world will be different then. He hopes Berkshire will be shareholder oriented—that is, managers treating shareholders as partners, doing with shareholder money exactly what the managers would be doing with their own money and not seeking an edge on the shareholders. Munger, speaking to the younger shareholders in attendance, advised them to keep the faith and suggested they would likely do worse if they trade their Berkshire stock for something else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;
	Questions Related to Investing and Investments&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Asked about interest rates and investing in bonds given inflation, Federal Reserve actions, and the likelihood of more U.S. Treasury bonds coming to auction, Buffett said he doesn’t know where &lt;strong&gt;interest rates&lt;/strong&gt; are going. No one does, including the Fed, given all the factors involved, but Buffett thinks long-term bonds at current rates are a terrible investment. The Fed says it wants inflation to be 2%, and the long bond yields a little over 3%. That doesn’t deliver much real return, especially if you pay taxes. Munger explained that what the Fed did in lowering interest rates in the recession wasn’t fair to older people with savings accounts, but it had to be done. He has only seen interest rates drop and stay low for so long this one time in his lifetime. Equity investors benefited from low rates driving asset prices up. Buffett said bonds had pretty much been unattractive ever since the 1940s, with the exception of the early 1980s, when they offered a 14% return that you could lock in for 30 years. &lt;strong&gt;Every now and then, something strange happens in markets&lt;/strong&gt; to present opportunities like that. The trick is to be prepared when it happens and take action when it does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Noting Berkshire’s increased investment in Apple, Buffett was asked why he never bought &lt;strong&gt;Microsoft&lt;/strong&gt;, given his close relationship with Bill Gates. Buffett blamed his stupidity in earlier years of getting to know Gates and then later, once Gates had come on Berkshire’s board, Buffett didn’t think it was appropriate, as he worried about appearances. The opportunity for others to think Buffett had gained some inside insight from knowing Gates was too great. (&lt;strong&gt;Buffett values his and Berkshire’s reputation highly&lt;/strong&gt;. He often notes that what can take a lifetime to build can be lost in five minutes of reckless behavior.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Asked to describe a &lt;strong&gt;formula approach&lt;/strong&gt; for how to look for mispriced investments, Buffett replied he can’t give a formula approach because he doesn’t use one. He looks at the facts, and if there isn’t a meaningful difference between the price and the value, he moves on. Munger added that when he looked at Costco at 13 times earnings, it seemed too cheap given its competitive strengths and other advantages. If you want formulas and theories, go to graduate school, and they will give you a lot of formulas that don’t work in practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;quote&quot; style=&quot;padding: 15px;&quot;&gt;
	Buffet doesn&#039;t think either China or the U.S. would dig itself into a real trade war. He thinks we&#039;ve learned the lessons of the past on those. Elements of U.S. policy will irritate others just as elements of other irritate the U.S. All presidents need to be the educators-in-chief to explain to the people what is happening and why.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Observing that Berkshire has made a lot of money investing in &lt;strong&gt;low capital-intensive businesses&lt;/strong&gt;, like See’s Candies, American Express and GEICO, a questioner wondered why Buffett abandoned this approach for more &lt;strong&gt;highly capital-intensive businesses&lt;/strong&gt;, like Burlington Northern Railroad. Buffett answered that he always prefers buying businesses with high returns on investment that require little reinvestment at the right prices, but Berkshire has moved into capital-intensive businesses that are nevertheless good businesses because Berkshire generates more cash than it can reinvest otherwise. It gets a good return despite the capital intensity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Buffett was asked what factors lead him to call &lt;strong&gt;cryptocurrency&lt;/strong&gt; a bubble. In answering, Buffett referenced his earlier discussion of productive versus nonproductive assets. When you buy a productive asset, you can figure what it is worth based on what it produces. With a nonproductive asset, you are counting on someone else to later pay more for it. That can work for a while and sometimes climbs to extraordinary numbers, but it comes to a bad ending. It was tried before with tulip bulbs. On top of nothing being produced, cryptocurrency attracts a lot of charlatans with less-than-stellar character. Buffett also cited checks as an example. Being able to write checks or wire money is a wonderful idea, but it doesn’t make the check itself intrinsically worth a lot of money. Asked for his thoughts, Munger said he likes cryptocurrency even less than Buffett does. He likened professional traders and investment houses jumping into trading crypto to seeing somebody else making a lot of money trading “turds” and deciding you can’t be left out!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Buffett was asked for his reassessment of an article he contributed to in 1999 for &lt;i&gt;Fortune&lt;/i&gt; magazine predicting lower future investment returns based in part on after-tax &lt;strong&gt;corporate profits&lt;/strong&gt; not staying above 6% of GDP, given that profits had run consistently higher in recent years. Buffett commented that American business in aggregate has become incredibly more profitable in the last 20 years because of the new companies and industries that developed. Many of the newer companies are higher margined and asset light, whereas the older companies are more asset intensive. The margins on the older companies haven’t risen all that much, but he didn’t anticipate the developments in the newer companies in 1999. Munger added that Buffett got the margin prediction wrong then, but he invested correctly and was accurate in his performance prediction for the stock market. That shows how hard it is to make these sort of predictions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Noting Buffett and Munger have been critical of what &lt;strong&gt;business schools&lt;/strong&gt; teach about investing, they were asked if good investing just comes back to chapter 8 of Benjamin Graham’s book &lt;i&gt;The Intelligent Investor&lt;/i&gt;, which deals with market fluctuations. Buffett said he went to three different business schools—Wharton, University of Nebraska and Columbia—and he found a teacher or two at each from whom he learned a lot, Ben Graham in particular at Columbia. But business schools strayed from the reality of investing with the efficient market theory about 40 years ago. Buffett credited Munger as being an amazing teacher. Anytime you find someone who challenges you and gives you insights into things you didn’t understand before, it makes you better. Munger added that if you don’t keep learning and revising earlier thoughts with better ones, you will end up like “a one-legged man in an ass-kicking contest.” You have to keep learning; what you formerly knew is never enough. Munger said he often uses that metaphor but asked anyone with a better one to pass it along. (Even at 94, Munger is looking for a better way to express himself!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Investing well doesn’t require a superior IQ or an MBA from a top school. Investing is not super complicated, but does require discipline. A few aspects are very important: innately understanding the lessons of chapter eight in &lt;i&gt;The Intelligent Investor&lt;/i&gt; and understanding accounting. It also helps if you have a consumer mindset toward the products of businesses. A consumer mindset helps in seeing the business differences between Coca-Cola and RC Cola, American Express and Diners Club in the early days of credit cards, or See’s Candies and a no-name competitor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Quoting an &lt;strong&gt;Elon Musk&lt;/strong&gt; comment that moats are lame and nice in a quaint, vestigial way, but what matters is the pace of innovation, a shareholder asked Buffett if &lt;strong&gt;business moats&lt;/strong&gt; are still relevant in the face of so much technological change. Buffett explained that he isn’t talking about a literal body of water but the business advantages that protect the profitability of an economic castle from competitive invaders. Moats come in many forms, but competitors are always trying to cross them. The pace of attack has accelerated, and some moats have become more susceptible to attack, but the idea is to build and maintain strong defenses to protect the economic castle. He cited being the low-cost provider in an essential service like GEICO or the brand recognition of See’s Candies as effective moats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Munger answered a question on the use of &lt;strong&gt;machine intelligence&lt;/strong&gt; in capital allocation, saying machines can do some things better than humans, like the game of Go, but there is a lot of hype in the field. Though machine intelligence will have business uses, individual investors should not expect to gain much from it in their investing. In capital allocation, you’re trying to get the best of what’s worth getting over time. People try to reduce investing to a formula that a machine can apply. He calls this physics envy, but the world isn’t like physics outside of physics itself. Master the general ideas and don’t get caught up in false precision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Referencing Buffett’s admonition that energy devoted to patching a chronically leaking boat is often better spent changing boats, a questioner asked if &lt;strong&gt;Wells Fargo&lt;/strong&gt; is a chronic leaker and if Buffett would switch. Buffett explained that corporations make mistakes, and sometimes those mistakes create investment opportunities. He cited Berkshire’s original investment in GEICO in the 1970s and the Buffett Partnership’s investment in American Express in the 1960s as examples of bargains created by fixable business mistakes. It’s important for companies to have systems to alert them to wrong behavior and to fix them when they become aware of them. Wells Fargo’s incentives encouraged some bad behavior, but then Wells compounded the problem by not immediately addressing it. Buffett likes Tim Sloan, who became CEO at Wells after the sales incentive revelations in 2016, and his efforts to fix those past mistakes. He felt Wells would be a well-run bank going forward, and Munger agreed, saying Wells was likely to be the best-behaved bank in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;
	Stock Buybacks&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Asked whether &lt;strong&gt;Apple&lt;/strong&gt; should be buying back $100 billion of its stock or making acquisitions with the money, Buffett said he was delighted with buybacks as long as the company is doing it below its intrinsic value. With Apple’s ongoing buyback, Berkshire’s nearly 5% stake in it could grow to 6% or 7% in a few years without Berkshire investing another dime. He doubted Apple could create the same value with $100 billion of acquisitions, as the prices wouldn’t be remotely as sensible for acquired companies as for Apple’s own shares, plus Apple knows its own business better than any it might buy. Buffett noted that the math of the buyback would get even better if Apple’s shares went down (but not its intrinsic value), something people often misunderstand. Munger added that most companies don’t create shareholder value with acquisitions, so buybacks can be advantageous, but they don’t approve of buybacks that are just trying to hold a share price up or that are at prices above intrinsic value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	To a question about the growth in Berkshire’s cash balances, Buffett explained that if cash grew beyond what they thought they could invest well, they would look for the most tax-efficient way to return it to shareholders. A buyback would be more tax efficient than a dividend, but they wouldn’t do a buyback above intrinsic value, as that would hurt continuing shareholders while paying a premium to those leaving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;
	Trade Wars and China&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Asked if there is a win-win outcome for both China and the U.S. in trade and other rivalries, Buffett explained that China and the U.S. are going to be the superpowers of the world economically and otherwise for a long time to come. We have common interests, but there will be tension too. Trade is a win-win situation for both sides, but both sides may do some mildly foolish things also. But the benefits of trade are too big and obvious for two intelligent countries to do something extremely foolish. The world has done very well with trade. The problem happens when one side wants to win a little too much and then tensions arise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Munger added that both countries have been advancing, with China advancing more quickly because it started from a much lower base. Of course, a country like China, mired in poverty, that adopts the technology of the world and has a high savings rate is going to advance faster than a far more developed economy. He is optimistic that the two countries will be smart enough to realize the last thing they should do is have ill will for the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Asked how trade tariffs affect Berkshire, Buffett cited the steel it uses in manufacturing as a cost that has risen. He continued that he didn’t think either China or the U.S. would dig itself into a real trade war. He thinks we’ve learned the lessons of the past on those. Elements of U.S. policy will irritate others just as elements of others irritate the U.S., but it will settle down in the end. Buffett thinks the U.S. president—every president—needs to be an educator-in-chief, to explain to the people what is happening and why. Trade is hard to explain because the benefits of it, though large in aggregate, are small individually and hard to see. For example, if the U.S. had a rule that only TV sets made here could be sold here, we’d pay a lot more for TVs, but without that rule, it’s hard to see clearly how much we are benefiting from importing those made elsewhere. However, the costs of trade are easier to see individually when it’s your factory or job that goes away. The good part of trade is shared collectively, but the bad part is focused on smaller groups. Some of those hurt can move on to other things, but many can’t, and society has to take care of those who can’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;
	2019 Annual Shareholder Meeting&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	The next meeting will occur on Saturday, May 4, 2019, in Omaha, Nebraska. Omaha is a nice weekend getaway with a number of attractions in addition to the annual meeting events. Make your plans early if you would like to attend, as hotels and planes fill up. Alternatively, the meeting will be webcast.&amp;nbsp;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/sites/default/files/u1/b-box-logo.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 12px; height: 16px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyLine&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	The views expressed are those of Brown Advisory as of the date referenced and are subject to change at any time based on market or other conditions. These views are not intended to be and should not be relied upon as investment advice and are not intended to be a forecast of future events or a guarantee of future results. Past performance is not a guarantee of future performance and you may not get back the amount invested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;padding: 5px 0px 0px; line-height: 1.5em; font-size: 0.7em;&quot;&gt;
	The information provided in this material is not intended to be and should not be considered to be a recommendation or suggestion to engage in or refrain from a particular course of action or to make or hold a particular investment or pursue a particular investment strategy, including whether or not to buy, sell, or hold any of the securities or asset classes mentioned. It should not be assumed that investments in such securities or asset classes have been or will be profitable. To the extent specific securities are mentioned, they have been selected by the author on an objective basis to illustrate views expressed in the commentary and do not represent all of the securities purchased, sold or recommended for advisory clients. The information contained herein has been prepared from sources believed reliable but is not guaranteed by us as to its timeliness or accuracy, and is not a complete summary or statement of all available data. This piece is intended solely for our clients and prospective clients, is for informational purposes only, and is not individually tailored for or directed to any particular client or prospective client.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     <pubDate>Wednesday, August 1, 2018 - 08:50</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Hutch Vernon, CFA</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">&lt;a href=&quot;/en/theadvisory/2018-berkshire-hathaway-annual-shareholder-meeting&quot;&gt;24496&lt;/a&gt;</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>&lt;a href=&quot;/en/en/theadvisory/toll-collection&quot;&gt;Toll Collection&lt;/a&gt;</title>
    <link>/en/en/theadvisory/toll-collection</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;span style=&quot;color:#003399; font-size:18px; font-family:georgia,serif;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Flexible Equity Strategy’s&amp;nbsp;Maneesh&amp;nbsp;Bajaj&amp;nbsp;discusses the power of “tollbooth” business models and how they fit into the strategy’s overall philosophy of seeking out durable companies with attractive economics. This approach to finding companies with staying power has helped Flexible Equity outperform notably over its 30-year history and during the recent period as&amp;nbsp;Maneesh&amp;nbsp;has partnered with Hutch Vernon in managing the strategy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Most of us experience tollbooths (or the modern automated equivalents) as a simple, unavoidable fact of life. If there is a clearly superior route to get from point A to point B, we take it—and if there is a small toll charged for that route, we most likely pay the toll rather than choose an inferior route. The operator of the toll system, meanwhile, is in a highly enviable position—it can simply sit back and enjoy the reward of its strategically advantageous position.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	This concept has been a powerful strategic metaphor over the years for investors like Warren Buffett and others who focus heavily on finding business models with distinct and sustainable advantages. &lt;strong&gt;In managing the Flexible Equity Strategy, my partner, Hutch Vernon, and I are highly attracted to “tollbooth companies” that collect steady streams of revenue via excellent strategic positioning, durable competitive advantages and high barriers to entry that prevent new participants from dislodging them.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #e6ebf7; padding: 10px;&quot;&gt;
	&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot; class=&quot;responsiveImg&quot;&gt;
		&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.brownadvisory.com/sites/default/files/u1/toll_charts_modified2.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://www.brownadvisory.com/sites/default/files/u1/toll_charts_modified2.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 740px; height: 435px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 0.8em; line-height: 14px;&quot;&gt;
		Source: FactSet. The portfolio information provided is based on a representative Brown Advisory Flexible Equity account as of 06/30/2018 and is provided as supplemental information. Composite performance is based on the Brown Advisory Institutional Flexible Equity Composite, managed by Brown Advisory Institutional. Brown Advisory Institutional is a division of Brown Advisory LLC and Brown Advisory Institutional is a GIPS compliant firm. Returns greater than one year are annualized. Past performance is not indicative of future results. Please see the Brown Advisory Institutional Flexible Equity Composite performance disclosure on the back cover for additional information and a complete list of terms and definitions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyLine&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	We are long-term investors, so for us, buying a stock is equivalent to buying a business. Companies with these tollbooth characteristics have the potential to generate attractive and reliable cash flows for shareholders for very long periods of time. Over the years, we have found these opportunities in many different industry sectors, from financial services to health care to technology. As of June 30, 2018, these companies represented over 30% of our portfolio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;
	Three Keys to Success for Tollbooth Companies&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Not every company can pull off a winning tollbooth business model. Broadly speaking, there are three key elements to such models if they are to succeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol class=&quot;one-column-list&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;strong&gt;&lt;i&gt;Small, incremental collections:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; A tollbooth business generally collects a small sliver of an industry’s economic activity. These small tolls or charges, while modest individually, can add up incrementally to a meaningful total.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;strong&gt;&lt;i&gt;Less attractive alternatives:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; There is a stickiness to these business models. Building a new road as an alternative to an existing toll road, for example, is often futile given prohibitive costs and resources. Drivers or customers are less inclined to seek alternative routes and are willing to pay a small amount to access a system or toll road that provides them the most efficient route.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;strong&gt;&lt;i&gt;Pricing and scale flexibility:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; The tollbooth operator benefits from pricing power and minimal capital requirements. Further, if the capital requirements for supporting incremental traffic and maintenance are not high, this would be an attractive recipe for wealth generation over time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	When all of these conditions are met and a tollbooth business has a strong grip on a high-volume market, it is often in a good position to generate attractive returns on capital for an extended period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;
	Financial Services Examples: The Network Might of Visa and Mastercard&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Visa and Mastercard are wonderful business models with tollbooth-like characteristics. They have created competing namesake payment networks that connect merchants, cardholders, banks, card issuers and other institutions that sign up merchants to join their networks. These payment networks facilitate electronic fund transfers throughout the world. Visa and Mastercard charge a small “toll” (interchange) for the electronic transactions that ride on their networks. In return, they provide an important service of securely transferring payment information as well as clearing and settling payments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	The two companies dominate the global payment-processing systems market. Global card purchase volume (excluding China) reached $13 trillion in 2017, according to the World Bank; Visa reported that $7.3 trillion flowed across its network, and Mastercard reported $3.8 trillion in volume, so collectively they own more than 85% of the market. As early movers and dominant players, the two companies combined have attracted more than two billion consumers and more than 40 million merchants to their networks, so both companies now benefit from enormous scale advantages. As mentioned above, trillions of dollars flow over these network “highways” every year, with minimal incremental investment required from Visa or Mastercard. The barriers for new entrants are extremely high—to compete effectively would require decades of investment in technology and marketing to attract consumers, merchants and banks, so there is little incentive for competitors to try to replicate these networks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	With strong moats of protection and high returns on capital, Visa and Mastercard are prime examples of tollbooth businesses. The factors discussed above helped drive our decision to invest in both companies early, at the time of their initial public offerings. The investments in Visa and Mastercard have both had meaningful contributions to our returns over several years of our holding periods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;
	Managed Health Care Examples: Sitting Astride Rising Costs&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	The U.S. managed health care sector is an attractive industry in which leaders have benefited from a tollbooth position that sits astride continually rising health care spending. While many other countries operate single-payer public health care systems, about 90% of the U.S. population manages its health care costs through an insurance plan—primarily through the government (Medicare and Medicaid) or through employers, who all generally contract with health insurers to administer the plans. Insurers have created constrained networks of medical providers and negotiated lower rates for services from those providers. The providers benefit from the volume provided by the network, and the participants benefit from the lower cost of care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	In other words, the insurers act as metaphorical tollbooth operators for health care. The only alternative to bypassing these “tolls” (which come in the form of annual or monthly premiums) is to pay the full cost of health care. While a commuter might seek an alternate route to avoid a toll, very few people will choose to pay full price at the doctor’s office in order to avoid participating in a health plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	In the modern health care system, with its evolving standards of care, new drugs in the marketplace, higher drug prices and overall skyrocketing costs, scale is a huge advantage for U.S. insurers. The biggest insurers have the most leverage in negotiating prices with providers, and they can also spread heavy fixed spending on technology and other areas across their millions of participants. Over the years, leading managed care companies like UnitedHealth, Anthem and Aetna have built that kind of scale, cementing their leadership positions with favorable relationships with care providers, pharmacies, and suppliers of medical supplies and devices. At this stage of the industry’s evolution, building a similar network from scratch, and the infrastructure to serve it, would be next to impossible within a time frame that would make the investment attractive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Managed care companies comprise approximately 5% of the Flexible Equity portfolio. Tollbooth characteristics and rising health care costs are big drivers of our investment thesis in these companies. We invested in UnitedHealth in the third quarter of 2017, which we especially like due to its superior use of data to drive better patient outcomes. Given positive industry tailwinds in the form of rising health care spending, we think firms like UnitedHealth can be attractive long-term holdings for the foreseeable future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyLine&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot; class=&quot;responsiveImg&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.brownadvisory.com/sites/default/files/u1/tollbooth_companiestable_2.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Sampling of tollbooth companies in the Flexible Equity portfolio&quot; src=&quot;http://www.brownadvisory.com/sites/default/files/u1/tollbooth_companiestable_2.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 800px; height: 614px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;
	The Future for Tollbooths: No Need to Slow Down&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Physical tollbooths are being replaced by more modern technologies, but in business, the tollbooth concept is still very much alive. In fact, technology trends are opening up more opportunities for these businesses, from mobile payment systems to social media advertising. For enterprise owners and investors, we believe that tollbooth companies will be attractive business models that can generate high capital returns over long periods of time.&amp;nbsp;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/sites/default/files/u1/b-box-logo.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 12px; height: 16px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyLine&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.brownadvisory.com/en/disclosures/flex-composite&quot;&gt;Click here to view Flexible Equity Composite Disclosures&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	The views expressed are those of Brown Advisory as of the date referenced and are subject to change at any time based on market or other conditions. These views are not intended to be and should not be relied upon as investment advice and are not intended to be a forecast of future events or a guarantee of future results. Past performance is not a guarantee of future performance and you may not get back the amount invested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;padding: 5px 0px 0px; line-height: 1.5em; font-size: 0.7em;&quot;&gt;
	The information provided in this material is not intended to be and should not be considered to be a recommendation or suggestion to engage in or refrain from a particular course of action or to make or hold a particular investment or pursue a particular investment strategy, including whether or not to buy, sell, or hold any of the securities or asset classes mentioned. It should not be assumed that investments in such securities or asset classes have been or will be profitable. To the extent specific securities are mentioned, they have been selected by the author on an objective basis to illustrate views expressed in the commentary and do not represent all of the securities purchased, sold or recommended for advisory clients. The information contained herein has been prepared from sources believed reliable but is not guaranteed by us as to its timeliness or accuracy, and is not a complete summary or statement of all available data. This piece is intended solely for our clients and prospective clients, is for informational purposes only, and is not individually tailored for or directed to any particular client or prospective client.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     <pubDate>Tuesday, July 31, 2018 - 10:39</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Maneesh Bajaj, CFA</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">&lt;a href=&quot;/en/theadvisory/toll-collection&quot;&gt;24486&lt;/a&gt;</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>&lt;a href=&quot;/en/en/theadvisory/financial-cost-food-waste&quot;&gt;The Financial Cost of Food Waste&lt;/a&gt;</title>
    <link>/en/en/theadvisory/financial-cost-food-waste</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;
	We all remember being told to clean our plates when we were kids. Unfortunately, that advice hasn’t stopped food waste from becoming a massive problem in the U.S. At Brown Advisory’s recent “Boston Innovates” event on sustainable food systems, we convened a panel of experts and leaders who are working towards food waste solutions. (The event was held in connection with our sponsorship of the &lt;i&gt;U.S. Food Waste Summit&lt;/i&gt;, held June 26–27 at Harvard University.)&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.brownadvisory.com/sites/default/files/u1/food_waste_pic.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/sites/default/files/u1/food_waste_pic.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px; height: 220px; float: right; padding: 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Food waste—defined simply as food produced but not eaten—has more than tripled in the U.S. since 1960 and grown by 50 percent since 1990, and as much as 40% of all food in the U.S. goes to waste at some point in the supply chain, according to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nrdc.org/sites/default/files/wasted-2017-report.pdf&quot;&gt;2017 report from the Natural Resources Defense Council (NRDC)&lt;/a&gt;. This represents a massive setback in terms of hunger; reducing food waste by just one-third would be enough to feed all of the 42 million Americans who face food insecurity. It’s also a problem for climate change—almost all uneaten food in the U.S. ends up rotting in landfills, where organic matter accounts for 16 percent of U.S. methane emissions, according to the Environmental Protection Agency. Finally, food waste is responsible for massive financial losses—the value of food wasted in the U.S. currently comes in at approximately $218 billion per year, according to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.refed.com/?sort=economic-value-per-ton&quot;&gt;ReFED&lt;/a&gt;, a nonprofit focused on reducing food waste,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	While cleaning our plates might help, it wouldn’t come close to solving the problem entirely. ReFED&#039;s analysis shows that about 43% of food waste in 2015 was generated by households, but the majority occurred&amp;nbsp;elsewhere—farms, manufacturers, grocery stores, shipping losses and restaurants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	As sustainable investors, one of the things we look for are challenges that create financial costs and thus opportunities to reduce those costs. Food waste is certainly one of those challenges, as shown in the chart below. The cost for end consumers that pay retail prices for food is highest, but there are meaningful costs across the food supply chain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyLine&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot; class=&quot;responsiveImg&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.brownadvisory.com/sites/default/files/u1/foodwaste_chart_v2.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;The Financial Cost of Food Waste&quot; src=&quot;/sites/default/files/u1/foodwaste_chart_v2.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 750px; height: 343px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 0.8em;&quot;&gt;
	Source: ReFED&amp;nbsp;(annualized estimates updated as of Mar. 31, 2016).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyLine&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	These costs create opportunities for a variety of businesses. In some cases, companies are able to reduce their own costs (and by definition improve their profit margins); for example, Marriott International is focusing meaningfully on food waste, and recently set a waste reduction goal of 50% percent by 2025. It participated in a pilot project of the American Hotel &amp;amp; Lodging Association that lowered overall food costs by more than 3 percent—a meaningful figure for a business that operates on relatively thin margins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	In other cases, firms can turn these costs into revenue opportunities, by creating new products and services that help their customers reduce food waste. Ecolab is a good example; it works with many grocery stores and other distributors of food that end up wasting food due to poor labeling (unclear labeling on products and shelves can often lead to premature disposal of food fit to be eaten). Ecolab’s Prep-N-Print program, according to the company, assists in waste reduction through automating the labeling process and capturing accurate product shelf life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Food waste touches multiple issues that present material risks and opportunities to investors, from the immediate cost of discarded products to the longer-term implications of climate change. We believe that corporations will need to play a big role in a comprehensive long-term food waste solution, and the companies who proactively address this challenge may find ample opportunity to drive revenue and profit along the way.&amp;nbsp;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/sites/default/files/u1/b-box-logo.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 12px; height: 16px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyLine&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	The views expressed are those of Brown Advisory as of the date referenced and are subject to change at any time based on market or other conditions. These views are not intended to be and should not be relied upon as investment advice and are not intended to be a forecast of future events or a guarantee of future results. Past performance is not a guarantee of future performance and you may not get back the amount invested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;padding: 5px 0px 0px; line-height: 1.5em; font-size: 0.7em;&quot;&gt;
	The information provided in this material is not intended to be and should not be considered to be a recommendation or suggestion to engage in or refrain from a particular course of action or to make or hold a particular investment or pursue a particular investment strategy, including whether or not to buy, sell, or hold any of the securities or asset classes mentioned. It should not be assumed that investments in such securities or asset classes have been or will be profitable. To the extent specific securities are mentioned, they have been selected by the author on an objective basis to illustrate views expressed in the commentary and do not represent all of the securities purchased, sold or recommended for advisory clients. The information contained herein has been prepared from sources believed reliable but is not guaranteed by us as to its timeliness or accuracy, and is not a complete summary or statement of all available data. This piece is intended solely for our clients and prospective clients, is for informational purposes only, and is not individually tailored for or directed to any particular client or prospective client.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     <pubDate>Friday, July 27, 2018 - 08:01</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Katherine Kroll</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">&lt;a href=&quot;/en/theadvisory/financial-cost-food-waste&quot;&gt;24416&lt;/a&gt;</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>&lt;a href=&quot;/en/en/theadvisory/strong-defense-falling-opportunity-cost-allocating-bonds&quot;&gt;Strong Defense: The Falling Opportunity Cost of Allocating to Bonds&lt;/a&gt;</title>
    <link>/en/en/theadvisory/strong-defense-falling-opportunity-cost-allocating-bonds</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;
	For years, “defense” in portfolios—i.e., allocations to cash and core fixed income holdings—has meant a willingness to accept extremely low returns. But after many years of economic recovery, we finally have reached a point where defensive allocations once again provide a reasonable yield.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Many noisy political topics have dominated the investment discourse in 2018, but underneath that noise and volatility, the drum beat of rising interest rates in the U.S. has been steady and consistent. After nearly a decade sitting near zero, the effective Fed Funds Rate (as tracked by the St. Louis Fed) rose above 50 bps at the end of 2016, and since then has ticked up to 180 bps as of June 30, 2018. While still low by historical standards, the Fed’s hiking has spurred rates elsewhere (the 10-year Treasury yield briefly poked above 3% in April, and now sits between 2.8% and 2.9%).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyLine&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot; class=&quot;responsiveImg&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.brownadvisory.com/sites/default/files/u1/bondmarket_yield_chart2.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;The U.S. bond market&#039;s yield is at its highest level in over eight years.&quot; src=&quot;/sites/default/files/u1/bondmarket_yield_chart2.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px; height: 525px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 0.8em;&quot;&gt;
	Source: Bloomberg.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyLine&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	As a result, it may make sense for investors to consider decreasing equity allocations and increasing fixed income allocations within their portfolios. (As always, such decisions are highly dependent on a given investor’s specific circumstances.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;
	Three Factors Supporting a Shift from Equities to Bonds&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	We still believe that equities offer healthy opportunity, and the fact that the current economic expansion is simply “old” has never been a sufficient reason for us to lose confidence in it. But beyond the economic cycle’s age, several factors suggest that a more defensive mindset is worth considering:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol class=&quot;one-column-list&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;strong&gt;Valuations are elevated.&lt;/strong&gt; This is true in various regions, but particularly true in the U.S. Robust Q1 2018 earnings growth improved the valuation picture for U.S. stocks, but they are still pricy by historical standards. It is worth noting that valuations are more reasonable in developed international and emerging markets; however, U.S. valuations are critical given the large role that U.S. stocks play in most investors’ core equity allocations.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;strong&gt;The economic expansion may be reaching its limits.&lt;/strong&gt; Rising interest rates, a flattening yield curve, continuing inflationary pressures and unemployment falling to multi-decade lows—we believe that all of these facts are indicative of an economy that is at or beyond full potential. The flattening curve has received a good deal of attention recently (the 2-year/10-year Treasury spread has narrowed to a mere 25 bps as of December 31, 2016), while the more traditional measures of employment and inflation have offered reasons for caution for some time. (We always emphasize, however, that we can’t predict the near-term direction of the economy and don’t base investment decisions on such predictions.)&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;strong&gt;Meaningful political and economic risks exist for stocks.&lt;/strong&gt; We discussed some of these risks at length in our 2018 asset allocation report, “Confronting the Unknown.” While the military threat in North Korea has, for now, appeared to recede, the potential impact of protectionist trends on global trade has only strengthened since we issued our report earlier this year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyLine&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot; class=&quot;responsiveImg&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.brownadvisory.com/sites/default/files/u1/useconomy_chart2.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Indicators point to a U.S. economy near full potential&quot; src=&quot;/sites/default/files/u1/useconomy_chart2.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px; height: 462px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 0.8em;&quot;&gt;
	Source: Bureau of Labor Statistics for unemployment data; Bureau of Economic Analysis for inflation data; U.S. Treasury for yield spread data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyLine&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	With all of this in mind, we believe that bonds have gained some ground on stocks in terms of the risk and potential reward each asset class represents. The opportunity cost of defense is lower today than it has been in many years.&amp;nbsp;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/sites/default/files/u1/b-box-logo.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 12px; height: 16px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyLine&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	The views expressed are those of Brown Advisory as of the date referenced and are subject to change at any time based on market or other conditions. These views are not intended to be and should not be relied upon as investment advice and are not intended to be a forecast of future events or a guarantee of future results. Past performance is not a guarantee of future performance and you may not get back the amount invested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;padding: 5px 0px 0px; line-height: 1.5em; font-size: 0.7em;&quot;&gt;
	The information provided in this material is not intended to be and should not be considered to be a recommendation or suggestion to engage in or refrain from a particular course of action or to make or hold a particular investment or pursue a particular investment strategy, including whether or not to buy, sell, or hold any of the securities or asset classes mentioned. It should not be assumed that investments in such securities or asset classes have been or will be profitable. To the extent specific securities are mentioned, they have been selected by the author on an objective basis to illustrate views expressed in the commentary and do not represent all of the securities purchased, sold or recommended for advisory clients. The information contained herein has been prepared from sources believed reliable but is not guaranteed by us as to its timeliness or accuracy, and is not a complete summary or statement of all available data. This piece is intended solely for our clients and prospective clients, is for informational purposes only, and is not individually tailored for or directed to any particular client or prospective client.&lt;br /&gt;
	&lt;br /&gt;
	&lt;strong&gt;Yield-to-Worst (YTW)&lt;/strong&gt; is the lowest potential yield that can be received on a bond without the issuer actually defaulting. The YTW is calculated by making worst-case scenario assumptions on the issue by calculating the return that would be received if the issuer uses provisions, including prepayments, calls or sinking funds. This metric is used to evaluate the worst-case scenario for yield to help investors manage risks and ensure that specific income requirements will still be met even in the worst scenarios.&lt;br /&gt;
	&lt;strong&gt;Bloomberg Barclays U.S. Aggregate Bond Index&lt;/strong&gt; is a market capitalization-weighted index, meaning the securities in the index are weighted according to the market size of each bond type. Most U.S. traded investment grade bonds are represented. Municipal bonds, and Treasury Inflation-Protected Securities are excluded, due to tax treatment issues. The index includes Treasury securities, Government agency bonds, Mortgage-backed bonds, Corporate bonds, and a small amount of foreign bonds traded in U.S.&lt;br /&gt;
	Bloomberg Barclays Indices are trademarks of Bloomberg or its licensors, including Barclays Bank PLC.&lt;br /&gt;
	BLOOMBERG, BLOOMBERG PROFESSIONAL, BLOOMBERG MARKETS, BLOOMBERG NEWS,BLOOMBERG ANYWHERE, BLOOMBERG TRADEBOOK, BLOOMBERG BONDTRADER, BLOOMBERG TELEVISION, BLOOMBERG RADIO, BLOOMBERG PRESS, BLOOMBERG.COM and BLOOMBERG LAW are trademarks and service marks of Bloomberg Finance L.P., a Delaware limited partnership, or its subsidiaries&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     <pubDate>Tuesday, July 24, 2018 - 09:00</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Taylor Graff, CFA</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">&lt;a href=&quot;/en/theadvisory/strong-defense-falling-opportunity-cost-allocating-bonds&quot;&gt;24461&lt;/a&gt;</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>&lt;a href=&quot;/en/en/theadvisory/529-plans-and-new-tax-code&quot;&gt;529 Plans And The New Tax Code&lt;/a&gt;</title>
    <link>/en/en/theadvisory/529-plans-and-new-tax-code</link>
    <description>&lt;h4&gt;
	You Can Now Use 529s for K-12 Costs—But Should You?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	The cost of college is growing at an astronomical rate, and Section 529 plans have long helped individuals and families grow assets earmarked for education in a tax-efficient manner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	The 2018 tax overhaul expanded the reach of 529 plans beyond college. As of this year, Federal law lets you distribute up to $10,000 each year from your 529 plan to fund primary (K-12) education tuition. But should you? Here are a few wrinkles to consider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;
	Your state may see things differently than the IRS.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	The first thing to consider is that 529 plans are governed at the state level. States vary widely in how they conform to federal tax law governing 529s—in other words, the IRS may not tax a distribution for K-12 tuition, but your state might.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	As it stands today, 31 states&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; conform to the federal tax code on 529 plans (see graphic). These states either exempt K-12 distributions from state taxes up to the $10,000 limit, or do not impose any state income tax (in which case the issue is not relevant).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;strong&gt;&lt;i&gt;If you reside in one of the other 19 states, you should review the current rules in your state AND look at whether your state is considering a change.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Some states impose state taxes and/or penalties on any withdrawals for K-12 tuition. In some cases, states allows current-year deductions for contributions into the 529, but a subset of those states are looking at rolling back those deductions if assets are ultimately used to fund K-12 education. The situation may be further complicated if you live in one state but invest in a 529 plan in another state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyLine&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot; class=&quot;responsiveImg&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.brownadvisory.com/sites/default/files/u1/529_map_chart.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;529 Plans and K-12 Expenses: A State-By-State Breakdown&quot; src=&quot;/sites/default/files/u1/529_map_chart.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px; height: 485px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 0.8em;&quot;&gt;
	Source: Brown Advisory. &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.savingforcollege.com/article/529-savings-plans-and-private-school-tuition#sfc-page-anchor-2&quot;&gt;https://www.savingforcollege.com/article/529-savings-plans-and-private-school-tuition#sfc-page-anchor-2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyLine&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;
	K-12 expenses will likely occur much sooner for you than college expenses. That impacts your investment equation.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Remember that 529 plans and other tax-deferred growth vehicles are most effective over longer periods of time, so that you can (potentially) benefit from the compounding effect of tax-free growth over many years. Over shorter periods, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;i&gt;there is less of a compounding effect to compensate you for the sacrifice of liquidity that comes with a tax-deferred vehicle.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	One specific point to consider: If you built your 529 asset allocation with a long-term target in mind (for example, 18 years from your child’s birth), it may be invested for long-term growth with a relatively heavy allocation to equities. If you decide now to use the plan to fund elementary education, those expenses may kick in for you just a few years after you’ve opened your 529. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;i&gt;In that case, your initial long-term allocation may no longer be appropriate for your adjusted short-term time horizon.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; So if you are interesting in using 529 assets for K-12 education, it is worth reviewing your investment selections to ensure the account’s allocation is in alignment with your new goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;
	Participation in a 529 plan impacts financial aid eligibility.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Lastly, 529s can impact financial aid eligibility, so whether you are deciding how much to contribute, when to withdraw, or even whether to have a 529 in your name, it is important to consider the impacts on the financial aid calculation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	The FAFSA application (Free Application for Federal Student Aid) combines several factors to calculate your Expected Financial Contribution (“EFC”), or the amount your family is deemed financially able to pay toward education. One key factor is who “owns” financial assets—up to 5.64% of non-retirement parent assets are deemed “available” for college costs, compared with up to 20% of student assets. Parent-owned 529 plans are typically counted as investment assets of the parents for the EFC calculation, so they are actually more favorable in this regard than student-owned assets such as UTMAs. The EFC calculation can also influence whether a grandparent should create their own 529 plan, or make contributions to a parent-owned plan instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Even if you have substantial wealth and financial aid is not a consideration for you, many states provide additional benefits for 529 assets, including scholarship provisions and creditor protection. Depending on your circumstances, there may be many reasons to keep 529 assets in place until college.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	As is often the case when tax law changes, just because a new option is &lt;i&gt;available&lt;/i&gt; does not mean it is always &lt;i&gt;advisable&lt;/i&gt;. The new flexibility for using 529 plans to fund K-12 expenses is certainly worth considering, but as always you should consult with qualified advisors to ensure you are looking at the bigger picture.&amp;nbsp;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/sites/default/files/u1/b-box-logo.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 12px; height: 16px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyLine&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	The views expressed are those of Brown Advisory as of the date referenced and are subject to change at any time based on market or other conditions. These views are not intended to be and should not be relied upon as investment advice and are not intended to be a forecast of future events or a guarantee of future results. Past performance is not a guarantee of future performance and you may not get back the amount invested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;padding: 5px 0px 0px; line-height: 1.5em; font-size: 0.7em;&quot;&gt;
	The information provided in this material is not intended to be and should not be considered to be a recommendation or suggestion to engage in or refrain from a particular course of action or to make or hold a particular investment or pursue a particular investment strategy, including whether or not to buy, sell, or hold any of the securities or asset classes mentioned. It should not be assumed that investments in such securities or asset classes have been or will be profitable. To the extent specific securities are mentioned, they have been selected by the author on an objective basis to illustrate views expressed in the commentary and do not represent all of the securities purchased, sold or recommended for advisory clients. The information contained herein has been prepared from sources believed reliable but is not guaranteed by us as to its timeliness or accuracy, and is not a complete summary or statement of all available data. This piece is intended solely for our clients and prospective clients, is for informational purposes only, and is not individually tailored for or directed to any particular client or prospective client. Any business or tax discussion contained in this communication is not intended as a thorough, in-depth analysis of specific issues.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     <pubDate>Tuesday, July 17, 2018 - 09:00</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Ariel Fortunato, CFP®, CTFA</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">&lt;a href=&quot;/en/theadvisory/529-plans-and-new-tax-code&quot;&gt;24411&lt;/a&gt;</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>&lt;a href=&quot;/en/en/theadvisory/take-esg-ratings-grain-salt&quot;&gt;Take ESG Ratings With A Grain Of Salt&lt;/a&gt;</title>
    <link>/en/en/theadvisory/take-esg-ratings-grain-salt</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;
	For good investors, a third-party rating system—for example, credit ratings from Moody’s or Fitch, or mutual fund star ratings—is usually just a first step in an investment decision-making process that involves a lot of other research and analysis. Yet when it comes to environmental, social and governance (ESG) research, a growing number of investors are keen to adopt a third-party rating system as the beginning and end of their process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	The simplicity of this idea is appealing. If you want to invest in “good” ESG companies and avoid “bad” companies, it would be wonderful to simply apply a prepackaged ratings screen to an index to achieve that result. To be clear, leading ESG research firms like MSCI and Sustainalytics have strong research teams and provide valuable information to thousands of investment firms, including ours. But if investors rely solely on the ratings built from that research to gauge an investment’s sustainable merits and risks, they will almost always miss out on key information that can only be surfaced through diligent, primary research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	There are several problems with leaning too heavily on ESG ratings. One specific challenge is a lack of standardization—every ratings system prioritizes different factors when defining a “good” ESG company. Some prioritize transparency and disclosure; others prioritize a company’s environmental or social track record or its past controversies; others prioritize current carbon emissions. Depending on which ratings service you choose, you may see wildly different results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Last year, Karina Funk and David Powell published a &lt;a href=&quot;//www.brownadvisory.com/en/theadvisory/esg-and-stock-%C2%ADpicker%E2%80%99s-dilemma&quot;&gt;journal article&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;in&amp;nbsp;the &lt;i&gt;Journal of Environmental Investing, &lt;/i&gt;that discusses the opportunities and challenges of using ESG information to improve investment decisions. In one section&amp;nbsp;of the article, we conducted an exercise to compare six leading ESG ratings schemes. We translated each firm’s ratings system into a consistent, 1-to-10 scale (1 representing the “worst” ESG score and 10 the “best”), then looked at how each firm rated the holdings in our firm’s Large Cap Sustainable Growth portfolio. The average result was a spread of nearly five points between the best and worst score—in other words, a typical company might receive a top-quartile rating from one ratings system, and a bottom-quartile rating from another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyLine&quot;&gt;
	&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 style=&quot;color:#003767;&quot;&gt;
	Eye of the Beholder: ESG Firms Rate Companies Very Differently&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 0.9em;font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;
	We looked at how six ESG ratings schemes rated a variety of companies (as of Dec. 31, 2016) covered by our research team. The difference between the “best” and “worst” ratings for each company is shown below—often, the gap is quite wide. (Ratings translated to a consistent 1-10 scale. Both the companies and ratings providers are anonymized for confidentiality purposes.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;responsiveImg&quot; style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;//www.brownadvisory.com/sites/default/files/u1/esg_chart.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Wide difference between best and worst ESG ratings for sampled portfolio companies&quot; src=&quot;/sites/default/files/u1/esg_ratings_chart.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 0.8em;&quot;&gt;
	Source: Brown Advisory. Each company depicted in the chart received a rating from all six research firms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyLine&quot;&gt;
	&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	For example, American Tower (a cellular tower company in which we’ve invested) currently receives a top rating from one leading ESG ratings system, and a rock-bottom rating from another. In the former case, the ratings analysis lauds American Tower for various factors, such as enabling communication in developing markets, and treating its workers well. In the latter case, the low rating is largely driven by a lack of transparency and disclosure on various matters. The key question here shouldn’t be which rating is correct—each firm’s analysis raises good points. Instead, investors should ask what they can learn from each of these ratings, to help them build a more complete picture. Our investment isn’t based on a 3rd-party rating; we invest due to strong company fundamentals and a solid ESG profile that, in our estimation, tangibly enhances American Tower’s business prospects. Specifically, it is the only tower operator to offer shared (and thus efficient) backup power generating capacity for the multiple carriers on its towers. Backup power is a critical need for carriers, who spend on the order of $15 billion per year in outages and degradation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	What we take away from this discussion is that ratings—whether you’re looking at mutual fund rankings, credit ratings or ESG grades—should not be viewed as an endpoint, but as the start of a research journey that spurs subsequent questions and more digging for information. In our view, no amount of raw ESG data can tell an investor whether a company is a sound fundamental investment—we believe that primary research is the only way to consistently drive well-informed investment decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	For more information about how we think about ESG information in our research, please review the full journal article we published on this topic, &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;//www.brownadvisory.com/en/theadvisory/esg-and-stock-%C2%ADpicker%E2%80%99s-dilemma&quot;&gt;ESG and the Stock Picker’s Dilemma&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/sites/default/files/u1/b-box-logo.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 12px; height: 16px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyLine&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	The views expressed are those of Brown Advisory as of the date referenced and are subject to change at any time based on market or other conditions. These views are not intended to be and should not be relied upon as investment advice and are not intended to be a forecast of future events or a guarantee of future results. Past performance is not a guarantee of future performance and you may not get back the amount invested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;padding: 5px 0px 0px; line-height: 1.5em; font-size: 0.7em;&quot;&gt;
	The information provided in this material is not intended to be and should not be considered to be a recommendation or suggestion to engage in or refrain from a particular course of action or to make or hold a particular investment or pursue a particular investment strategy, including whether or not to buy, sell, or hold any of the securities or asset classes mentioned. It should not be assumed that investments in such securities or asset classes have been or will be profitable. To the extent specific securities are mentioned, they have been selected by the author on an objective basis to illustrate views expressed in the commentary and do not represent all of the securities purchased, sold or recommended for advisory clients. The information contained herein has been prepared from sources believed reliable but is not guaranteed by us as to its timeliness or accuracy, and is not a complete summary or statement of all available data. This piece is intended solely for our clients and prospective clients, is for informational purposes only, and is not individually tailored for or directed to any particular client or prospective client.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     <pubDate>Monday, July 9, 2018 - 10:53</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Emily Dwyer , Karina Funk, CFA</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">&lt;a href=&quot;/en/theadvisory/take-esg-ratings-grain-salt&quot;&gt;24406&lt;/a&gt;</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>&lt;a href=&quot;/en/en/theadvisory/psychology-purpose-people-how-female-founders-are-building-new-ventures&quot;&gt;Psychology, Purpose, People: How Female Founders Are Building New Ventures&lt;/a&gt;</title>
    <link>/en/en/theadvisory/psychology-purpose-people-how-female-founders-are-building-new-ventures</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;
	Women wield more economic power and influence in the U.S. today than at any time in history. Women are increasingly starting new businesses and leading corporate, philanthropic, and government organizations. However, the story about women’s achievements is often defined relative to men’s achievement, and much of the discussion is centered on obstacles women face in closing the gender gap.&amp;nbsp;According to PitchBook,&amp;nbsp;female-founded startups raised $10.5 billion in venture funding in 2017—a healthy number but still just a small fraction of the $85 billion raised overall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	While it is important to acknowledge, address and eventually close these gaps, it’s essential to celebrate the achievements of female founders and to learn more about the businesses that these women are building. Our Female Founders panel discussion in New York on June 13 was designed to do just that. We were fortunate to have five impressive panelists—Anna Auerbach, co-founder of workplace flexibility innovator &lt;a href=&quot;https://werk.co/&quot;&gt;Werk&lt;/a&gt;; Lara Crystal, founder of &lt;a href=&quot;https://minibardelivery.com/&quot;&gt;Minibar Delivery&lt;/a&gt;; Tiffany Pham, founder and CEO of &lt;a href=&quot;https://onmogul.com/about&quot;&gt;Mogul&lt;/a&gt;; Geri Stengel, president of digital market research company &lt;a href=&quot;http://ventureneer.com/&quot;&gt;Ventureneer&lt;/a&gt;; and Susan Tynan, CEO and founder of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.framebridge.com/&quot;&gt;Framebridge&lt;/a&gt;. Through the panel’s conversation, three themes—&lt;i&gt;psychology, purpose and people&lt;/i&gt;—emerged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;strong&gt;Psychology:&lt;/strong&gt; Susan described her big, ambitious vision for Framebridge, which was met with an “invisible layer” of those doubting her ability to build an empire (a prejudice faced by women more than men, in her view). With that vision comes the need to embrace risk and the prospect of failure. Failure is a very possible outcome for a startup; but she reframed what failure meant to her. She views failure due to negligence or poor ethics as totally within her control, and is comfortable with the idea of failure for other reasons. She also said that experience is a great teacher when it comes to the volatility of an entrepreneurial life—once she experienced a few low points and got through them, she grew less fearful of them.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;strong&gt;Purpose:&lt;/strong&gt; Anna did not believe she had an entrepreneur’s mindset or what she described as founder DNA. However, she became obsessed with the desire to put more women in leadership roles and viewed flexibility as an obvious solution: If there are a greater number of flexible work environments that accommodate family responsibilities, there will be more opportunities for women to become leaders. Along the way, her vision about work/life balance expanded beyond just thinking about women. She realized that both men and women—families, really—could benefit from systems and support that allowed them to thrive simultaneously at work and at home. She felt obligated to build Werk because of this sense of purpose—she simply didn’t want to trust that another organization would see the solution as she did.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt; A common theme among the panelists was an intense focus on people—collaboration, mentorship, communication, empowerment. Lara learned the importance of a supportive, empowering environment at her previous company, Rent the Runway, and has worked to create a similar environment at Minibar. She and her co-founder Lindsey Andrews have a strong partnership built on support, which has greatly informed the company’s culture and hiring practices. Tiffany said that Mogul’s 100% employee retention rate is powered by communication, collaboration and celebration. For example, she proactively brings quieter people into group discussions, and ensures that the team comes together frequently to learn and celebrate together.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Overall, the evening’s discussion was a great celebration of the unique perspectives that women and men bring to a new venture. It is no surprise that the most effective and successful companies tend to be those that embrace diversity and allow all of those perspectives to flourish together.&amp;nbsp;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/sites/default/files/u1/b-box-logo.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 12px; height: 16px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyLine&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	The views expressed are those of Brown Advisory as of the date referenced and are subject to change at any time based on market or other conditions. These views are not intended to be and should not be relied upon as investment advice and are not intended to be a forecast of future events or a guarantee of future results. Past performance is not a guarantee of future performance and you may not get back the amount invested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;padding: 5px 0px 0px; line-height: 1.5em; font-size: 0.7em;&quot;&gt;
	The information provided in this material is not intended to be and should not be considered to be a recommendation or suggestion to engage in or refrain from a particular course of action or to make or hold a particular investment or pursue a particular investment strategy, including whether or not to buy, sell, or hold any of the securities or asset classes mentioned. It should not be assumed that investments in such securities or asset classes have been or will be profitable. To the extent specific securities are mentioned, they have been selected by the author on an objective basis to illustrate views expressed in the commentary and do not represent all of the securities purchased, sold or recommended for advisory clients. The information contained herein has been prepared from sources believed reliable but is not guaranteed by us as to its timeliness or accuracy, and is not a complete summary or statement of all available data. This piece is intended solely for our clients and prospective clients, is for informational purposes only, and is not individually tailored for or directed to any particular client or prospective client.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     <pubDate>Thursday, July 5, 2018 - 10:18</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Lisa Cuesta</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">&lt;a href=&quot;/en/theadvisory/psychology-purpose-people-how-female-founders-are-building-new-ventures&quot;&gt;24401&lt;/a&gt;</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>&lt;a href=&quot;/en/en/theadvisory/vertical-leap-what%25E2%2580%2599s-driving-vertical-software-companies&quot;&gt;Vertical Leap: What’s Driving Vertical Software Companies &lt;/a&gt;</title>
    <link>/en/en/theadvisory/vertical-leap-what%25E2%2580%2599s-driving-vertical-software-companies</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;
	In the software industry, the big, horizontal “platform” companies tend to attract the lion’s share of attention from investors and the financial media. Firms like Microsoft and Salesforce are household names at this point; other companies like Workday and ServiceNow are less familiar to the average person but quite well known to the investment community. These firms are appealing for many reasons. They serve huge total addressable markets (TAMs), often reaching $100 billion or more. They drive their results with massive sales teams. Nine-figure contracts with a single enterprise customer are not uncommon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Although our world is increasingly dominated by these large horizontal tech firms, we believe that investors should not ignore the potential of more narrowly focused vertical software companies. Many of these firms offer attractive earnings and cash flow growth potential—more than enough to make up for their smaller scale and addressable markets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	What are the success drivers for these vertical players?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;strong&gt;Focused research and development:&lt;/strong&gt; With a focus on a single industry or sector, these companies can concentrate their efforts on the features and analytics that their vertical specifically needs. In many cases, this allows them to outpace horizontal firms that need to serve many masters.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;strong&gt;Pricing power:&lt;/strong&gt; Being a “price maker” (vs. a “price taker”) in software usually requires either proprietary features or proprietary data sets, and the best vertical companies can often provide both. With respect to data, these firms are working with many of the leading competitors in a given vertical, allowing them to gather valuable market-wide datasets; they can provide that data back to their customers in an anonymized fashion, which gives those customers invaluable information about best practices in their industry and how they stack up against their peers.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;strong&gt;Lower customer acquisition costs:&lt;/strong&gt; Vertical firms typically exhibit notably lower sales and marketing expense than the average software company. One primary reason is referrals and/or reference accounts: Once a software company proves its mettle with a few admired firms in an industry, the other players in that industry are typically much more open to doing business with them. Additionally, these firms can tightly tailor their sales approach to dovetail with the unique vocabulary and operating models processes within a specific industry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Taken together, these advantages can help vertical companies build leading—sometimes dominant—market share, and achieve enviable operating margins. As shown in the chart below, vertical software firms generated better gross margins and lower sales &amp;amp; marketing costs than the broader industry in 2017. The end result: Vertical firms were almost twice as profitable as the industry average as measured by EBITDA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyLine&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot; class=&quot;responsiveImg&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.brownadvisory.com/sites/default/files/u1/vertical_leap_chart_2.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Fundamental Comparison, Vertical Software versus All Software (Calendar Year 2017)&quot; src=&quot;/sites/default/files/u1/vertical_leap_chart_2.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 750px; height: 382px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 0.8em;&quot;&gt;
	Source: Bloomberg. “All Software” refers to&amp;nbsp;NYSE- and NASDAQ-traded companies&amp;nbsp;categorized as Prepackaged Software&amp;nbsp;under the Standard Industrial Classification (SIC) system. “Vertical Software” refers to a subset of those companies whose revenue is&amp;nbsp; predominantly sourced from a specific vertical industry, according to&amp;nbsp;Brown Advisory analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyLine&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	There are a variety of examples that demonstrate the ability of these firms to gain primacy within their verticals: AspenTech serves the energy and chemicals industries, Tyler Technologies serves state and local governments, and Blackbaud works with nonprofits; all of these companies have&amp;nbsp;leading market share in their respective markets, and report winning as much as 80%&amp;nbsp;of the new contracts for which they compete. Veeva is notable as a CRM competitor in the pharmaceutical industry; the CRM market is increasingly dominated by Salesforce, but within this vertical, Veeva retains a 70%+ market share and its position is so strong that Salesforce has chosen to partner with Veeva rather than compete head-to-head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	The software universe will likely always have a group of titans that cast a long shadow over many industries, but vertically focused companies continue to prove their ability to carve out defensible positions, generate value for customers and perform well for shareholders.&amp;nbsp;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/sites/default/files/u1/b-box-logo.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 12px; height: 16px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyLine&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	The views expressed are those of Brown Advisory as of the date referenced and are subject to change at any time based on market or other conditions. These views are not intended to be and should not be relied upon as investment advice and are not intended to be a forecast of future events or a guarantee of future results. Past performance is not a guarantee of future performance and you may not get back the amount invested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;padding: 5px 0px 0px; line-height: 1.5em; font-size: 0.7em;&quot;&gt;
	The information provided in this material is not intended to be and should not be considered to be a recommendation or suggestion to engage in or refrain from a particular course of action or to make or hold a particular investment or pursue a particular investment strategy, including whether or not to buy, sell, or hold any of the securities or asset classes mentioned. It should not be assumed that investments in such securities or asset classes have been or will be profitable. To the extent specific securities are mentioned, they have been selected by the author on an objective basis to illustrate views expressed in the commentary and do not represent all of the securities purchased, sold or recommended for advisory clients. The information contained herein has been prepared from sources believed reliable but is not guaranteed by us as to its timeliness or accuracy, and is not a complete summary or statement of all available data. This piece is intended solely for our clients and prospective clients, is for informational purposes only, and is not individually tailored for or directed to any particular client or prospective client.&lt;br /&gt;
	BLOOMBERG, BLOOMBERG PROFESSIONAL, BLOOMBERG MARKETS, BLOOMBERG NEWS,BLOOMBERG ANYWHERE, BLOOMBERG TRADEBOOK, BLOOMBERG BONDTRADER, BLOOMBERG TELEVISION, BLOOMBERG RADIO, BLOOMBERG PRESS, BLOOMBERG.COM and BLOOMBERG LAW are trademarks and service marks of Bloomberg Finance L.P., a Delaware limited partnership, or its subsidiaries&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     <pubDate>Thursday, June 28, 2018 - 10:28</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Emily Wachtmeister, CFA</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">&lt;a href=&quot;/en/theadvisory/vertical-leap-what%E2%80%99s-driving-vertical-software-companies&quot;&gt;24376&lt;/a&gt;</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>&lt;a href=&quot;/en/en/theadvisory/arc-bond-covenants&quot;&gt;The Arc of the (Bond) Covenants&lt;/a&gt;</title>
    <link>/en/en/theadvisory/arc-bond-covenants</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;
	The warning &lt;i&gt;caveat emptor&lt;/i&gt;, or “buyer beware,” is particularly important to heed when investing in bonds late in the credit cycle. At those moments, issuers are pursuing more aggressive refinancing or acquisitions, underwriters are letting weaker credits slip through the cracks, and investors starved for yield are increasingly willing to hold their noses to outperform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Case in point: Two recent deals&amp;nbsp;highlighted what appear to be deteriorating underwriting standards and creditor protections, particularly prevalent in the high yield market where high-quality covenants—or just any covenants at all—are quickly becoming a “remember when” punchline. This deterioration has big implications for the speed and extremity of credit defaults, and for creditor recoveries once the cycle turns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;one-column-list&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		Hearthside, a packaged food supplier, was sold in a private equity transaction featuring 7x leverage. The deal initially included provisions limiting bondholders’ recourse to asset sale proceeds, very liberal secured financing capacity, and essentially unlimited dividend capacity, although it should be noted that creditor pushback resulted in key amendments that strengthened the covenant package.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		Another private equity transaction involving SRS Distribution also features generous add-backs to earnings that materially inflate the company’s debt capacity, as well as the ability to divert asset-sale proceeds to pay dividends to equity holders (where those proceeds are typically reserved for debt reduction).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Covenant quality deterioration (and aggressive PE activity) are lamentably old news. In fact, the renewed rigor in financial documentation following the crisis started disappearing almost as soon as it began. As shown in the chart below, the volume of covenant-light (commonly referred to as “cov-lite”) issuance has skyrocketed since the financial crisis. According to Moody’s, cov-lite leveraged loans made up 80% of all issuance in 2017—a far cry from 2012, when cov-lite loans were in the minority, not the majority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyLine&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;
	Letting Go of the Reins&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 13px;&quot;&gt;
	&lt;em&gt;Between June 2008 and May 2016, cov-lite debt issuance totaled about $1.14 trillion. Between June 2016 and May 2018, the total was $1.16 trillion. In other words, volume in the past two years exceeded that of the preceding &lt;strong&gt;eight&lt;/strong&gt; years.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot; class=&quot;responsiveImg&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.brownadvisory.com/sites/default/files/u1/arc_covenants_chart2.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Monthly Cov-Lite Issuance, 6/30/08-5/31/18&quot; src=&quot;/sites/default/files/u1/arc_covenants_chart2.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 902px; height: 367px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 0.8em;&quot;&gt;
	Source: Bloomberg.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyLine&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Experienced credit investors are generally wise to how credit cycles tend to unravel—badly—but such widespread acceptance of porous documentation and weak covenants has serious implications for &lt;i&gt;how quickly&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;how badly&lt;/i&gt; things can end in a given situation. Covenants generally act as triggers that slow an impending credit failure. Leverage maintenance covenants enable creditors to extract fees or impose restrictions on issuers that fail to meet them. Restricted payments rules prevent aggressive majority stakeholders from misappropriating liquidity when the issuer needs it most. Asset-sale and other distribution covenants ensure that actions taken by management result in healthier balance sheets, not healthier IRRs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Without these rules, creditors are often stuck watching a train wreck in slow motion, with little recourse or negotiating power. Situations like these often wind up in “free-fall” bankruptcy, leaving stakeholders little time or ability to preserve value, as the bankruptcy code intends. That means deeper losses at a much faster pace. So in this late-cycle, “buyer beware” environment, credit investors who ignore the role of covenants in mitigating default losses do so at their own peril.&amp;nbsp;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/sites/default/files/u1/b-box-logo.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 12px; height: 16px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyLine&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	The views expressed are those of Brown Advisory as of the date referenced and are subject to change at any time based on market or other conditions. These views are not intended to be and should not be relied upon as investment advice and are not intended to be a forecast of future events or a guarantee of future results. Past performance is not a guarantee of future performance and you may not get back the amount invested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;padding: 5px 0px 0px; line-height: 1.5em; font-size: 0.7em;&quot;&gt;
	The information provided in this material is not intended to be and should not be considered to be a recommendation or suggestion to engage in or refrain from a particular course of action or to make or hold a particular investment or pursue a particular investment strategy, including whether or not to buy, sell, or hold any of the securities or asset classes mentioned. It should not be assumed that investments in such securities or asset classes have been or will be profitable. To the extent specific securities are mentioned, they have been selected by the author on an objective basis to illustrate views expressed in the commentary and do not represent all of the securities purchased, sold or recommended for advisory clients. The information contained herein has been prepared from sources believed reliable but is not guaranteed by us as to its timeliness or accuracy, and is not a complete summary or statement of all available data. This piece is intended solely for our clients and prospective clients, is for informational purposes only, and is not individually tailored for or directed to any particular client or prospective client.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;padding: 5px 0px 0px; line-height: 1.5em; font-size: 0.7em;&quot;&gt;
	Private equity transactions may be available for Qualified Purchasers or Accredited Investors only. Internal rate of return (IRR) is a metric used in capital budgeting to estimate the profitability of potential investments. Internal rate of return is a discount rate that makes the net present value (NPV) of all cash flows from a particular project equal to zero. IRR calculations rely on the same formula as NPV does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;padding: 5px 0px 0px; line-height: 1.5em; font-size: 0.7em;&quot;&gt;
	BLOOMBERG, BLOOMBERG PROFESSIONAL, BLOOMBERG MARKETS, BLOOMBERG NEWS,BLOOMBERG ANYWHERE, BLOOMBERG TRADEBOOK, BLOOMBERG BONDTRADER, BLOOMBERG TELEVISION, BLOOMBERG RADIO, BLOOMBERG PRESS, BLOOMBERG.COM and BLOOMBERG LAW are trademarks and service marks of Bloomberg Finance L.P., a Delaware limited partnership, or its subsidiaries.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     <pubDate>Tuesday, June 26, 2018 - 16:11</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Tom Bandurowski, CFA</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">&lt;a href=&quot;/en/theadvisory/arc-bond-covenants&quot;&gt;24311&lt;/a&gt;</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>&lt;a href=&quot;/en/en/theadvisory/low-correlation-stocks-good-opportunity-active-managers&quot;&gt;Low Correlation in Stocks: A Good Opportunity for Active Managers&lt;/a&gt;</title>
    <link>/en/en/theadvisory/low-correlation-stocks-good-opportunity-active-managers</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;
	In equity markets, even the best active managers tend to struggle when stocks are all moving in lock step with each other. But when there’s more differentiation in returns across stocks and sectors, there’s more opportunity for managers to generate alpha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	We have seen a great deal of differentiation in the S&amp;amp;P 500&lt;sup&gt;®&lt;/sup&gt; Index so far in 2018 (see chart below). With all its ups and downs, the Index currently sits close to where it started the year, but underneath that flat number there’s been widely divergent sector performance. 2018 results highlight a few persistent themes at play in the market this year. (All return figures cited refer to sectors and subsectors of the S&amp;amp;P 500 Index).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyLine&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot; class=&quot;responsiveImg&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.brownadvisory.com/sites/default/files/u1/low_correlation_chart_4.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;S&amp;amp;P 500 Index: GICS Sector Performance, YTD as of 5/31/2018&quot; src=&quot;/sites/default/files/u1/low_correlation_chart_4.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 800px; height: 464px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;font-size:.8em;&quot;&gt;
	Source: Bloomberg.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyLine&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;strong&gt;Technology upswing:&lt;/strong&gt; The tech sector is up 10% so far this year, and drilling further down, the application software subsector is up more than 25% and the internet retail subsector is up more than 40%. Investors are very clearly rewarding this body of big technology companies that have built powerful economies of scale and positive network effects in recent years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	While valuations are rising in the space, earnings growth has also been notable this year in the technology sector, with earnings up 8.1% so far in 2018 vs. 4.3% for the Index overall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;strong&gt;Renaissance for…department stores?&lt;/strong&gt; Department store stocks that were left for dead last year are among the best performing stocks so far in 2018—the department store subsector is up more than 22% year to date. Few would argue that brick and mortar retail companies have a rosy, long-term outlook, but sometimes hard-hit stocks and sectors present true value opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;strong&gt;Doldrums for consumer staples:&lt;/strong&gt; At the other end of the spectrum, consumer staples is off more than 12% for the year; the packaged foods subsector is down more than 17%. The sector has been punished by a variety of factors from e-commerce disruption, to price competition, to an increasing reliance on leveraged M&amp;amp;A activity to bolster growth—all of which has been a recipe for pressure on already-low profit margins, and for poor stock performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;strong&gt;Reckoning for “bond proxies”:&lt;/strong&gt; For years after the financial crisis, investors fled to higher-yielding stocks and sectors (for example, stocks in the utilities, REIT and telecom sectors) for income that they couldn’t get from the bond market. These stocks have lagged the market considerably this year; the yield on 10-year U.S. Treasuries rose above 3% in April, and bonds are viewed once again as a viable source of income. Even cash (using one-to-three month T-bills for a proxy) is yielding near 2% today vs. a near-zero yield as recently as 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;
	Active managers benefiting from more return differentiation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	More differentiation between stocks has coincided with better results from active managers. According to Morningstar, 43% of active managers outpaced their passive counterparts in 2017, a notable improvement from 2016 when only 26% outperformed. Of course, an environment with greater differentiation merely provides opportunity for an active manager—it does NOT guarantee that the manager will capitalize on that opportunity. But with prudence, patience and a disciplined investment process, good managers are often able to extract value when the market offers a large spread in returns between fundamental winners and losers.&amp;nbsp;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/sites/default/files/u1/b-box-logo.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 12px; height: 16px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyLine&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	The views expressed are those of Brown Advisory as of the date referenced and are subject to change at any time based on market or other conditions. These views are not intended to be and should not be relied upon as investment advice and are not intended to be a forecast of future events or a guarantee of future results. Past performance is not a guarantee of future performance and you may not get back the amount invested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;padding: 5px 0px 0px; line-height: 1.5em; font-size: 0.7em;&quot;&gt;
	The information provided in this material is not intended to be and should not be considered to be a recommendation or suggestion to engage in or refrain from a particular course of action or to make or hold a particular investment or pursue a particular investment strategy, including whether or not to buy, sell, or hold any of the securities or asset classes mentioned. It should not be assumed that investments in such securities or asset classes have been or will be profitable. To the extent specific securities are mentioned, they have been selected by the author on an objective basis to illustrate views expressed in the commentary and do not represent all of the securities purchased, sold or recommended for advisory clients. The information contained herein has been prepared from sources believed reliable but is not guaranteed by us as to its timeliness or accuracy, and is not a complete summary or statement of all available data. This piece is intended solely for our clients and prospective clients, is for informational purposes only, and is not individually tailored for or directed to any particular client or prospective client.&lt;br /&gt;
	&lt;br /&gt;
	The &lt;strong&gt;Standard &amp;amp; Poor&#039;s 500® Index&lt;/strong&gt; is a market capitalization weighted index of the 500 largest U.S. publicly traded companies by market value. The S&amp;amp;P 500 is a market value or market capitalization weighted index and one of the most common benchmarks for the broader U.S. equity markets. Other common U.S. stock market benchmarks include the Dow Jones Industrial Average (DJIA) or Dow 30 and the Russell 2000 Index, which represents the small-cap index.&lt;br /&gt;
	Standard &amp;amp; Poor’s, S&amp;amp;P, and S&amp;amp;P 500® are registered trademarks of Standard &amp;amp; Poor’s Financial Services LLC (“S&amp;amp;P”), a subsidiary of S&amp;amp;P Global Inc.&lt;br /&gt;
	Morningstar, Inc., Morningstar, the Morningstar logo and Morningstar.com are registered trademarks of Morningstar, Inc. All other Morningstar products and proprietary tools, including Morningstar Category, Morningstar Rating, Morningstar Risk, Morningstar Return, and Morningstar Style Box are trademarks of Morningstar, Inc.&lt;br /&gt;
	The Global Industry Classification Standard (GICS) was developed by and is the exclusive property of MSCI and Standard &amp;amp; Poor’s. “Global Industry Classification Standard (GICS), “GICS” and “GICS Direct” are service marks of Standard &amp;amp; Poor’s and MSCI. “GICS” is a trademark of MSCI and Standard &amp;amp; Poor’s.&lt;br /&gt;
	BLOOMBERG, BLOOMBERG PROFESSIONAL, BLOOMBERG MARKETS, BLOOMBERG NEWS,BLOOMBERG ANYWHERE, BLOOMBERG TRADEBOOK, BLOOMBERG BONDTRADER, BLOOMBERG TELEVISION, BLOOMBERG RADIO, BLOOMBERG PRESS, BLOOMBERG.COM and BLOOMBERG LAW are trademarks and service marks of Bloomberg Finance L.P., a Delaware limited partnership, or its subsidiaries&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     <pubDate>Tuesday, June 19, 2018 - 09:13</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>J.R. Rodrigo</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">&lt;a href=&quot;/en/theadvisory/low-correlation-stocks-good-opportunity-active-managers&quot;&gt;24306&lt;/a&gt;</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>&lt;a href=&quot;/en/en/theadvisory/fed-meeting-its-all-about-expectations&quot;&gt;The Fed Meeting: It’s All about Expectations&lt;/a&gt;</title>
    <link>/en/en/theadvisory/fed-meeting-its-all-about-expectations</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;
	On Wednesday, the Federal Open Market Committee concluded its June meeting. There was a lot to digest: Another 25bp rate hike, clearer signals about two more hikes in 2018, a new set of economic projections, and Fed Chairman Powell’s press conference. Here are some of our team’s initial thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;
	The rate hike was no surprise&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	This rate hike was widely expected. Before the meeting, most investors also foresaw another hike in September, and were split on another in December. Now, expectations will likely solidify around two more hikes this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	To state the obvious, market prices are based on expectations. We are less concerned about additional Fed rate hikes if they are expected and telegraphed. We are more focused on the Fed’s “reaction function”—in other words, on the events and trends that might disrupt the Fed’s current pattern. What are the intervening events that might interrupt the Fed’s plans—causing them to either halt its hikes or accelerate them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;
	The “dot plot” shows little change&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	The Fed’s reaction function is a big reason why the new Summary of Economic Projections (SEP) is worth some additional scrutiny. This report includes the infamous &quot;dot plot,&quot; a chart that depicts each FOMC member&#039;s view on where the Fed&#039;s rate target should be based on his or her economic outlook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	The media often focuses on the median viewpoint among FOMC members, which can shroud the Fed’s broader view. In this report, the median FOMC view on the year-end rate moved from 2.125% (implying three total hikes this year) to 2.375% (implying four). But the shift was due to a single member moving their forecast—all other members’ views were unchanged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;
	The Fed seems comfortable with inflation trends&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Lately, inflation indicators have nudged higher, but Powell did not signal more aggressive hikes to stem inflation. He suggested that the uptick is likely due to transitory factors from 2017 rebounding, and stated that “if we thought inflation would take off, we would be showing higher rates.” The lack of major movement in the dot plot suggests that the committee largely agrees with this view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;
	Along with consistency, there’s uncertainty&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Despite the consistency in messaging this year, there are clearly events that could derail the Fed’s current path. He largely deflected questions on how a bigger deficit, rising corporate leverage or a potential trade war might impact the economy. At the same time, he stated that the Fed was likely nearing a “neutral” rate that is neither stimulating nor constricting the economy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	We need to acknowledge that the Fed may not be able to stay “neutral” and may have to speed up or slow down its trajectory if events unfold in an unexpected way. When you consider that monetary policy is also near neutral, it all adds up to a narrow margin of error for the Fed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;
	Conclusion: Don’t play the expectations game&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Bond investors need to respect that uncertainty may impact interest rates and economic growth. Rather than placing bets on uncertain economic outcomes, we prefer to focus on fundamental credit analysis and remain flexible. Flexible investors can watch for moments when a big consensus swing opens up an attractive entry point for a solid investment.&amp;nbsp;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/sites/default/files/u1/b-box-logo.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 12px; height: 16px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyLine&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	The views expressed are those of Brown Advisory as of the date referenced and are subject to change at any time based on market or other conditions. These views are not intended to be and should not be relied upon as investment advice and are not intended to be a forecast of future events or a guarantee of future results. Past performance is not a guarantee of future performance and you may not get back the amount invested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;padding: 5px 0px 0px; line-height: 1.5em; font-size: 0.7em;&quot;&gt;
	The information provided in this material is not intended to be and should not be considered to be a recommendation or suggestion to engage in or refrain from a particular course of action or to make or hold a particular investment or pursue a particular investment strategy, including whether or not to buy, sell, or hold any of the securities or asset classes mentioned. It should not be assumed that investments in such securities or asset classes have been or will be profitable. To the extent specific securities are mentioned, they have been selected by the author on an objective basis to illustrate views expressed in the commentary and do not represent all of the securities purchased, sold or recommended for advisory clients. The information contained herein has been prepared from sources believed reliable but is not guaranteed by us as to its timeliness or accuracy, and is not a complete summary or statement of all available data. This piece is intended solely for our clients and prospective clients, is for informational purposes only, and is not individually tailored for or directed to any particular client or prospective client.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     <pubDate>Thursday, June 14, 2018 - 11:45</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Thomas Graff, CFA</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">&lt;a href=&quot;/en/theadvisory/fed-meeting-its-all-about-expectations&quot;&gt;24346&lt;/a&gt;</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>&lt;a href=&quot;/en/en/theadvisory/now-2018-conference-our-investment-team%25E2%2580%2599s-roundtable-recap&quot;&gt;NOW 2018 Conference: Our Investment Team’s Roundtable Recap&lt;/a&gt;</title>
    <link>/en/en/theadvisory/now-2018-conference-our-investment-team%25E2%2580%2599s-roundtable-recap</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;i&gt;The NOW conference is always memorable, but this year’s conference included some particularly compelling and provocative ideas. I wanted to make sure we considered those ideas and their implications for the portfolios we manage for our clients, with truly open minds. So, after the NOW conference, I invited a number of colleagues to join me for dinner so we could gather in a comfortable off-site environment, free of distractions, and connect the dots between what we heard at NOW and what we’re thinking about as investors. I&#039;d like to thank my colleagues&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.brownadvisory.com/en/people/lisa-cuesta&quot;&gt;Lisa Cuesta&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.brownadvisory.com/en/people/taylor-graff-cfa&quot;&gt;Taylor Graff&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.brownadvisory.com/en/people/amy-hauter-cfa&quot;&gt;Amy&amp;nbsp;Hauter&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.brownadvisory.com/en/people/jane-korhonen-cfa&quot;&gt;Jane&amp;nbsp;Korhonen&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.brownadvisory.com/en/content/private-client-team-portfolio-manager-stephanie-mccormick&quot;&gt;Stephanie McCormick&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.brownadvisory.com/en/people/adi-padva&quot;&gt;Adi&amp;nbsp;Padva&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.brownadvisory.com/en/people/keith-stone-caia&quot;&gt;Keith Stone&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.brownadvisory.com/en/people/lyn-white-cfa&quot;&gt;Lyn White&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;for their contributions to a rousing and wide-ranging discussion.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;i&gt;I was not surprised at all when the conversations started at a polarizing moment from the conference. At one point, Skip Gates brought up the concept of reparations for historical injustices against African-Americans. If you attended NOW, you’ll remember the nearly physical reaction that rippled throughout the auditorium when the word “reparations” was spoken. A good number of attendees recoiled in displeasure and an equivalent number perked up eagerly.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;i&gt;What pleased me to no end was that our entire group said that they enthusiastically welcomed that uncomfortable moment, and other uncomfortable moments that occasionally occur at our NOW conferences. They all believe what I believe, which is that the point of NOW is to not just to expose us to provocative ideas. We want the conference to force us to open our eyes, look at those new ideas, and consider whether we should respond by redirecting our actions and energies along a more fruitful path.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;i&gt;Our group covered a wide range of topics during a freewheeling two-hour conversation. I’ve done my best to capture the more interesting takeaways in the summary you&#039;ll find on the next few pages. There is no doubt that the NOW conference, and our small group’s recap conversation, addressed many important questions about the future of society; in this write-up, we have tried to keep the focus on our efforts to invest successfully for our clients.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;
	On the Social and Environmental Factors That Are Driving Business and Investing&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Race, gender, political and identity schisms are roiling our society to an extent not seen since the civil rights era. While the direct ties to our work as investors may not be immediately obvious, they are definitely there: We strongly believe that the companies that thrive over the long term will be the ones that can openly address these challenges and in so doing find opportunities for growth. Moreover, we want to be one of those companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	In that vein, it was interesting to hear the results of the&amp;nbsp;Edelman&amp;nbsp;Trust survey in the session led by Matt Harrington,&amp;nbsp;Edelman&#039;s&amp;nbsp;COO. We heard that people are losing faith in governments and placing more trust in corporations; notably, 64% of respondents want CEOs to take the lead on a lot of society’s issues. Jane&amp;nbsp;Korhonen, a portfolio manager in our Washington, D.C . office, saw this as an almost unimaginable shift in trust away from traditional institutions and toward corporations to solve the world’s problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	But the shift is occurring nonetheless. I asked Lisa Cuesta and Keith Stone, both of whom focus on the startup/venture universe, for their thoughts on the movement among startups to align business with mission. They are both seeing a lot more mission-aligned thinking on the part of companies and venture funds alike. In many cases, mission drives passion, and this passion can be a powerful force for startups in their initial push to get off the ground. They said, that mission is often a clear catalyst for recruitment, customer delight and business growth; one example is Grove Collaborative, a firm whose entire business is based on providing “clean living” e-ecommerce—a collection of organic household products made available through a subscription service. There is no real reason for that company to exist—there are plenty of ways to get organic household products already. But Grove succeeds because it is so passionate and mission-driven. This drives their people, the information they offer, the community they’ve built. They’ve earned a position as a deeply trusted source and beloved brand, and grown very rapidly. In this case, the mission alignment drove their superb execution, which led to success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Taylor Graff noted that today’s corporate environment is truly different than what it was 20 years ago: in the past, profit versus mission was a binary choice and a trade-off, but today, markets, consumers and prospective employees have all shifted considerably in a manner that allows companies to earn positive ROI when they allocate capital in line with their mission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	With this in mind, I asked&amp;nbsp;Adi&amp;nbsp;Padva, Lyn White and Amy&amp;nbsp;Hauter—all of whom examine public companies for us in the equity and credit markets—how they engage with companies on these social and environmental issues. They all identified the surge in the number of companies that proactively address these issues today in quarterly presentations, versus just a few years ago. Sustainability is becoming almost a required component of corporate presentations to the investment community; however, companies vary widely, and they also noted the need to be watchful and separate authentic business commitments from&amp;nbsp;greenwashing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Amy also noted that the merits of an investment may be straightforward when it comes to financial returns, but mission-related evaluation is more subjective. She cited a number of renewable energy bonds we own that were issued under the Green Bond Principles, so we know that the proceeds are going to good projects. But some of those bonds are issued by oil companies, utilities that also burn coal and so forth. Investors will respond differently to these—some are uncomfortable with the issuers, while others are pleased by the positive environmental impacts produced by the projects being funded. We consider all of these things when we invest, but we need to make sure we’re transparent about what we own and why so our clients can make these judgment calls for themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;
	On Artificial Intelligence&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	This year’s conference was subtitled “Humanity in a Time of Intelligent Machines,” and the ramifications of AI were discussed throughout the day—not just the viability of the technology, but the challenges of integrating AI into society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Lisa shared an interesting anecdote related to self-driven cars, a market that is providing a spark for AI innovation. When she worked at Google, she wrote an internal article about her fear of driving, and as a result the company invited her into its pilot program for autonomous vehicles. She commuted in a self-driving car for an extended period, and the car worked perfectly. This was in 2013. The technology is there. Her point was that the big hurdles for AI will be just as much about adoption, acceptance and psychology as they will be about the technology itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	We asked each other for guesses on when we will see the tipping point for autonomous vehicles and what will catalyze the big push for driverless vehicles to become the rule, not the exception. No one wanted to take the bait with a specific guess—a moment of pride for me, we strongly discourage speculation at our firm!—but a number of folks were quite optimistic about anticipated progress.&amp;nbsp;Adi&amp;nbsp;noted that there are some really strong business drivers here and that they may override resistance faster than some think. Insurance companies will factually benefit from driverless cars, based on the actuarial numbers. The cost for the self-driving systems are declining rapidly. And constant connection with mobile devices makes driving less desirable for people, and FAR less desirable for a family whose kids are learning to drive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	On the question of who will win the driverless vehicle race, Keith noted that in the end, miles driven will be a key success factor, both for developing robust technology and for winning approval from regulators. Google has a big head start, and new entrants face the natural and financial limits on how many physical miles a given company can record in a day. But he cited&amp;nbsp;Zoox, a portfolio company of one of our venture managers, as an example of a company using AI creatively; it is using AI to run simulations of driving miles, which is letting the company build knowledge much faster than it could by logging physical miles on the road, and it is catching up rapidly with companies like Google. This approach is also helping&amp;nbsp;Zoox&amp;nbsp;in its efforts to&amp;nbsp;reimagine&amp;nbsp;cars from the ground up—it is testing vehicle concepts that depart significantly from standard vehicle designs, and virtual simulations allow them to evaluate various designs before building physical models.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	In terms of other applications for AI, Lisa noted that while we are still many years away from “real” AI, the machine learning capabilities available today can still be commercialized, and there are markets where this machine learning is in high demand.&amp;nbsp;NextGen&amp;nbsp;Venture Partners (which recently joined Brown Advisory) invested in a company called Customer Science that, in a nutshell, helps firms with a lot of customer data make use of that data. It has lots of offline customers with a dire need to compete with Amazon and other digitally native companies, and understand how their customers think and behave the way the digital companies do. Another example: Unilever bought Dollar Shave Club for $1 billion, and it&amp;nbsp;wasn’t because they’re selling $1 billion worth of razor blades—it was for the company’s ability to understand how its customers think and shop. It was DNA that Unilever&amp;nbsp;didn’t have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Jane raised the uncomfortable issue of how AI might directly affect the investment management business. She&amp;nbsp;doesn’t think we should fear losing our jobs to robots, and neither do I, but we both see AI as a great opportunity for companies like ours. She hopes to be able to use AI to better understand our clients; to better understand how to translate each client’s risk profile into concrete portfolio parameters; to better understand how clients they want to see information reported to them. I wholeheartedly agree, and I suspect that AI will affect our business in a lot of ways that&amp;nbsp;aren’t yet fully apparent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;
	On Trade Wars&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Taylor had a number of thoughts regarding the healthy debate on trade we enjoyed at the conference. Those who attended the conference heard a friendly but spirited debate over the merits of protectionism versus free trade. Rather than argue on one side or the other, Taylor noted that the policy developments we’ve seen this year are less about who’s right on trade and more about the fact that free trade opponents are winning the war of words among a wide swath of the voting public. As investors, we know that companies have been huge beneficiaries of free trade, and if they can’t successfully convince the public of the merits of free trade, they may lose the favorable environment they’ve enjoyed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	The U.S. has staked out a highly protectionist stance so far this year, at least by the standards of the last few decades of U.S. policy. Where we go from here is really in the hands of other countries and how they respond. As we have noted in other settings, we don’t want to venture guesses about how trade negotiations may play out, but we know that the overall environment is a bit of a minefield for multinational companies whose earnings guidance this year and next depend on free trade and open borders. As such, we’ve tried to account for this rising risk in our asset allocation work, leaning away from large caps and into smaller companies, in both the U.S. and emerging markets, whose businesses are relatively local and not dependent on exports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;
	On&amp;nbsp;Blockchain&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Everyone at our gathering agreed that&amp;nbsp;blockchain&amp;nbsp;technology offers enormous potential. But so far, the bulk of the activity in this market has been focused on&amp;nbsp;cryptocurrency, and as we’ve seen, participation in Bitcoin or other&amp;nbsp;cryptocurrencies&amp;nbsp;is really more about speculation at the moment than it is about investment in a disruptive technology. Lisa noted that&amp;nbsp;NextGen&amp;nbsp;has met with a number of companies in the past 12–18 months, some of which had pretty solid businesses—but these companies are becoming hopelessly distracted by the initial coin offering route and by trying to build convoluted business models around the issuance of their own currency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	I struggle to support arguments in favor of buying into&amp;nbsp;cryptocurrency&amp;nbsp;right now. Some people tout the network effect that will buoy a&amp;nbsp;cryptocurrency&amp;nbsp;if enough people get behind it, but the value of the currency today is largely based on its scarcity—it takes a significant investment of resources to produce even one incremental unit of Bitcoin. How can you build network effect when it is so hard to scale up volume? Lisa noted that proponents of these currency systems argue that their value stems from their stability and reliability in comparison to fiat currencies, especially from sovereign entities that perennially struggle with inflation. But that is also a tough argument to support given the volatility we see in the crypto market today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	The real issue with&amp;nbsp;cryptocurrency&amp;nbsp;is that it is a product created for the purpose of transacting, but it is still in the early stages of scaling up and does not yet make sense as a transaction medium. Keith noted that the wild speculative environment that has occurred around Bitcoin has essentially no relation to the eventual intended purpose of Bitcoin. Not only is the price far too volatile today, but it is still essentially cost-prohibitive to conduct Bitcoin transactions over normal financial channels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	But we have to recognize that even in its immature state, the market is building rapidly.&amp;nbsp;Coinbase&amp;nbsp;booked $1 billion in revenue last year, and it oversees more accounts than Charles Schwab. That’s a major company. Whether or not we think any of this makes sense right now, a lot of people do, and we need a view on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Lisa warned that this wave feels different than previous technology waves. In the past, the “nerds in the garage” were always the ones leading the charge at first, and the money followed behind. But with crypto, a lot of the early attention is just driven by the money pouring in. It remains to be seen whether the attention we’re seeing in the space translates to real transformation. When I think back to the dawn of the internet, we saw the creation of world-changing technology that started to change the world, but the early companies were eviscerated because they&amp;nbsp;didn’t really understand how to translate the technology into a really transformative business. We had companies like Pets.com trying to move traditional business models to the web in a very ham-handed fashion or companies that spent investor capital without restraint. There are for sure thoughtful people building thoughtful businesses around&amp;nbsp;blockchain&amp;nbsp;as we speak, but I also think it’s likely that 10 years from now, there will be transformative&amp;nbsp;blockchain&amp;nbsp;businesses that are not even scribbled on a napkin yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;
	On Philanthropy and Leadership&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	We were fortunate to hear from David&amp;nbsp;Rubenstein&amp;nbsp;during the NOW conference, and he gave us a lot to think about regarding how the successful and fortunate can think about giving back to the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Stephanie McCormick offered several thoughts during our dinner conversation about how&amp;nbsp;Rubenstein’s words related to her experience counseling clients on matters of philanthropy and legacy. She made a point of emphasizing how personal a matter it is when a client is exploring how much of their wealth they should give back. The Giving Pledge is a wonderful commitment, and we admire folks like Warren Buffett, Bill Gates and David&amp;nbsp;Rubenstein, who have signed up to give away a majority of their wealth to philanthropic causes. With any of our clients, we can only help them answer the question of “how much” through an extended series of conversations over time, in which we discuss family obligations, legacy goals, estate planning constraints and a host of other factors. The answer for everyone is different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	That being said, she really appreciated&amp;nbsp;Rubenstein’s discussion about aligning mission with giving. We have a number of clients at Brown Advisory who have come to us in just the past few years, and they really haven’t had people talk to them before about that alignment or encourage them to really explore that question of mission. It’s worth exploring, and sometimes you need a push to get outside your comfort zone. Helping your local community is of course an admirable and worthy goal, and in most communities, there are a variety of established structures to help you do that. When you define your mission more ambitiously (in&amp;nbsp;Rubenstein’s case, his mission is to help America be a better place—that’s fairly ambitious!), you can end up a little bit further out on a limb. There’s less structure to help you accomplish your goals, you probably need to work harder to define your goals crisply and you may want to be more creative in your activities. Obviously, we&amp;nbsp;aren’t all in a position to buy copies of the Magna&amp;nbsp;Carta&amp;nbsp;and essentially gift them to the public commons as&amp;nbsp;Rubenstein&amp;nbsp;has! But Stephanie felt strongly, and I certainly agree, that his model for thinking about philanthropy can be of value for a lot of our clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	In fact, I felt like the discussion of the&amp;nbsp;Rubenstein&amp;nbsp;session helped us to really pull together a lot of the lessons from the day and tie them to this fundamental notion that it’s wise to really open up our minds when it comes to how we can contribute and give back to society. We talked during the day about grand philanthropic efforts, about making investments in companies that think wisely about society, about the societal implications of technologies like AI, and about individual actions to build a more diverse and inclusive workplace or community. It all makes a difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/sites/default/files/u1/chewsig.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 150px; height: 78px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;greyLine&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	The views expressed are those of Brown Advisory as of the date referenced and are subject to change at any time based on market or other conditions. These views are not intended to be and should not be relied upon as investment advice and are not intended to be a forecast of future events or a guarantee of future results. Past performance is not a guarantee of future performance and you may not get back the amount invested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;padding: 5px 0px 0px; line-height: 1.5em; font-size: 0.7em;&quot;&gt;
	The information provided in this material is not intended to be and should not be considered to be a recommendation or suggestion to engage in or refrain from a particular course of action or to make or hold a particular investment or pursue a particular investment strategy, including whether or not to buy, sell, or hold any of the securities or asset classes mentioned. It should not be assumed that investments in such securities or asset classes have been or will be profitable. To the extent specific securities are mentioned, they have been selected by the author on an objective basis to illustrate views expressed in the commentary and do not represent all of the securities purchased, sold or recommended for advisory clients. The information contained herein has been prepared from sources believed reliable but is not guaranteed by us as to its timeliness or accuracy, and is not a complete summary or statement of all available data. This piece is intended solely for our clients and prospective clients, is for informational purposes only, and is not individually tailored for or directed to any particular client or prospective client.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     <pubDate>Thursday, June 14, 2018 - 10:27</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Paul J. Chew, CFA</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">&lt;a href=&quot;/en/theadvisory/now-2018-conference-our-investment-team%E2%80%99s-roundtable-recap&quot;&gt;24341&lt;/a&gt;</guid>
  </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
